<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Легкие on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/</link><description>Recent content in Легкие on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>ru</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. Two Sum</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement In this problem, you&amp;rsquo;re given an array of integers nums and an integer target. Your task is to find the indices of two numbers in the array that add up to the target. The input array is guaranteed to have exactly one solution, and you can&amp;rsquo;t use the same element twice. The indices can be returned in any order.
Naive Solution A naive solution would involve using two nested loops to iterate through each pair of elements in the array and check if their sum is equal to the target.</description></item><item><title>9. Palindrome Number</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/9/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/9/</guid><description>LeetCode задача
Задача Определите, является ли целое число палиндромом, не преобразуя его в строку.
Подсказки Переворачивая число и сравнивая его с оригиналом, мы можем определить, является ли оно палиндромом.
Подход Вместо того чтобы преобразовывать число в строку, мы можем перевернуть его цифры с использованием математических операций, а затем сравнить перевернутое число с оригинальным.
Алгоритм Если число отрицательное, то это не палиндром. Инициализируем переменную для перевернутого числа: мы будем создавать это число шаг за шагом. Переворачиваем число: Это достигается путем последовательного взятия последней цифры числа и добавления её к текущему общему количеству после сдвига текущих цифр этого общего числа.</description></item><item><title>13. Roman to Integer</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/13/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Roman numerals are represented by seven different symbols: I, V, X, L, C, D and M.
Symbol Value I 1 V 5 X 10 L 50 C 100 D 500 M 1000 For example, 2 is written as II in Roman numeral, just two ones added together. 12 is written as XII, which is simply X + II. The number 27 is written as XXVII, which is XX + V + II.
Roman numerals are usually written largest to smallest from left to right.</description></item><item><title>14. Longest Common Prefix</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/14/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/14/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Write a function to find the longest common prefix string amongst an array of strings.
If there is no common prefix, return an empty string &amp;quot;&amp;quot;.
Example 1:
Input: strs = [&amp;quot;flower&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;flow&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;flight&amp;quot;] Output: &amp;quot;fl&amp;quot; Example 2:
Input: strs = [&amp;quot;dog&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;racecar&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;car&amp;quot;] Output: &amp;quot;&amp;quot; Explanation: There is no common prefix among the input strings. First accepted Idea:
class Solution: def longestCommonPrefix(self, strs: List[str]) -&amp;gt; str: strs.sort() l = strs[0] r = strs[-1] if l == r: return l res = &amp;#34;&amp;#34; for i in range(0, len(l)): if l[i] == r[i]: res += l[i] else: return res return res</description></item><item><title>20. Valid Parentheses</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/20/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Given a string s containing just the characters '(', ')', '{', '}', '[' and ']', determine if the input string is valid.
An input string is valid if:
Open brackets must be closed by the same type of brackets. Open brackets must be closed in the correct order. Every close bracket has a corresponding open bracket of the same type. Example 1:
Input: s = &amp;quot;()[]{}&amp;quot; Output: true Example 2:
Input: s = &amp;quot;()[]{}&amp;quot; Output: true First accepted Idea:</description></item><item><title>21. Merge Two Sorted Lists</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/21/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/21/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
You are given the heads of two sorted linked lists list1 and list2.
Merge the two lists in a one sorted list. The list should be made by splicing together the nodes of the first two lists.
Return the head of the merged linked list.
Example 1:
Input: list1 = [1,2,4], list2 = [1,3,4] Output: [1,1,2,3,4,4] Example 2:
Input: list1 = [], list2 = [0] Output: [0] First accepted Idea:
Get smallest head. Loop and update its next.</description></item><item><title>26. Remove Duplicates from Sorted Array</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/26/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/26/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Given an integer array nums sorted in non-decreasing order, remove the duplicates in-place such that each unique element appears only once. The relative order of the elements should be kept the same.
Since it is impossible to change the length of the array in some languages, you must instead have the result be placed in the first part of the array nums. More formally, if there are k elements after removing the duplicates, then the first k elements of nums should hold the final result.</description></item><item><title>66. Plus One</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/66/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/66/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
You are given a large integer represented as an integer array digits, where each digits[i] is the ith digit of the integer. The digits are ordered from most significant to least significant in left-to-right order. The large integer does not contain any leading 0&amp;rsquo;s.
Increment the large integer by one and return the resulting array of digits.
Example 1:
Input: digits = [1,2,3] Output: [1,2,4] Explanation: The array represents the integer 123. Incrementing by one gives 123 + 1 = 124.</description></item><item><title>69. Sqrt(x)</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/69/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/69/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Given a non-negative integer x, return the square root of x rounded down to the nearest integer. The returned integer should be non-negative as well.
You must not use any built-in exponent function or operator.
For example, do not use pow(x, 0.5) in c++ or x ** 0.5 in python.
Example 1:
Input: x = 4 Output: 2 Explanation: The square root of 4 is 2, so we return 2. Example 2:
Input: x = 8 Output: 2 Explanation: The square root of 8 is 2.</description></item><item><title>70. Climbing Stairs</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/70/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/70/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
You are climbing a staircase. It takes n steps to reach the top.
Each time you can either climb 1 or 2 steps. In how many distinct ways can you climb to the top?
Example 1:
Input: n = 2 Output: 2 Explanation: There are two ways to climb to the top. 1. 1 step + 1 step 2. 2 steps Example 2:
Input: n = 3 Output: 3 Explanation: There are three ways to climb to the top.</description></item><item><title>88. Merge Sorted Array</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/88/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/88/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
First accepted class Solution: def merge(self, nums1: List[int], m: int, nums2: List[int], n: int) -&amp;gt; None: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; Do not return anything, modify nums1 in-place instead. &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; i = len(nums1) - n for j in nums2: nums1[i] = j i += 1 nums1.sort()</description></item><item><title>94. Binary Tree Inorder Traversal</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/94/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/94/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Given the root of a binary tree, return the inorder traversal of its nodes' values.
Example 1:
Input: root = [1,null,2,3] Output: [1,3,2] Example 2:
Input: root = [] Output: [] Example 3:
Input: root = [1] Output: [1] Thoughts Don&amp;rsquo;t understand what needed. Why:
1-null-2-3 becomes 1-3-2 [1,2,5,7,8,9,10] becomes [7,2,8,1,9,5,10] In 1-null-2-3 1 becomes the first because we loop to its left node which is null, then come back and first value here is 1.</description></item><item><title>104. Maximum Depth of Binary Tree</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/104/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/104/</guid><description>LeetCode задача 104
Задача Дан корень бинарного дерева. Задача состоит в том, чтобы найти его максимальную глубину. Глубина бинарного дерева определяется как максимальное количество узлов на пути от корня дерева до любого листового узла, включая сам корень.
Подсказки Бинарное дерево представляет собой иерархическую структуру, в которой каждый узел имеет максимум двух потомков: левого и правого.
Подход / Идея решения Чтобы найти максимальную глубину бинарного дерева, можно использовать рекурсивный метод. Для каждого узла дерева, максимальная глубина поддерева с этим узлом в качестве корня будет равна максимуму из глубин левого и правого поддеревьев, увеличенному на 1 (сам узел).</description></item><item><title>118. Pascal's Triangle</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/118/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/118/</guid><description>LeetCode задача 118
Задача Дано целое число numRows. Верните первые numRows строк Треугольника Паскаля.
В Треугольнике Паскаля каждое число является суммой двух чисел, находящихся непосредственно над ним.
Подсказки Для построения каждой следующей строки можно использовать последнюю строку в текущей итерации. Например, если есть строка [1, 2, 1], то следующая строка начнется и закончится с 1, а числа внутри будут получены путем сложения пар чисел: 1+2 и 2+1.
Подход Для того чтобы построить Треугольник Паскаля, начнем с первой строки, состоящей только из числа 1.</description></item><item><title>141. Linked List Cycle</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/141/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/141/</guid><description>LeetCode problem 141
Problem Statement The problem asks us to determine if a given linked list contains a cycle. A cycle in a linked list occurs when a node&amp;rsquo;s next pointer points back to a previous node in the list, causing an infinite loop.
Hints &amp;amp; Tips In this problem, you can take advantage of the Floyd&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Tortoise and Hare&amp;rdquo; cycle detection algorithm. This algorithm allows you to detect a cycle in O(1) space and O(n) time complexity, where n is the number of nodes.</description></item><item><title>160. Intersection of Two Linked Lists</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/160/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/160/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Solution 1 Using hashmap.
# Definition for singly-linked list. class ListNode: def __init__(self, x): self.val = x self.next = None class Solution: def getIntersectionNode(self, headA: ListNode, headB: ListNode): nodes = set() cur = headA while cur: nodes.add(cur) cur = cur.next cur = headB while cur: if cur in nodes: return cur cur = cur.next return None Solution 2 Initialize two pointers, one for each head. Move each pointer to the next node in its list. If a pointer reaches the end of its list, move it to the start of the other list.</description></item><item><title>171. Excel Sheet Column Number</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/171/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/171/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
The column titles in an Excel sheet are designed similar to a base-26 number system. The columns start from &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; (which is 1) to &amp;lsquo;Z&amp;rsquo; (which is 26), then after &amp;lsquo;Z&amp;rsquo;, the column titles go to &amp;lsquo;AA&amp;rsquo; (which is 27), &amp;lsquo;AB&amp;rsquo; (28), and so on.
This problem is essentially asking us to convert a base-26 number (represented by uppercase English letters) to a decimal number.
That means that for each &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; index in columnTitle we already pass alphabet.</description></item><item><title>190. Reverse Bits</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/190/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/190/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
This task involves understanding how binary representation works. An unsigned integer is a 32-bit value, where each bit represents a power of 2, from 2^0 (the least significant bit) to 2^31 (the most significant bit).
Unsigned Integers (often called &amp;ldquo;uints&amp;rdquo;) are just like integers (whole numbers) but have the property that they don&amp;rsquo;t have a + or - sign associated with them. Thus they are always non-negative (zero or positive).
Naive Solution A naive solution to this problem could involve converting the number to a binary string, reversing the string, and then converting it back to an integer.</description></item><item><title>191. Number of 1 Bits</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/191/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/191/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given an integer value represented in binary format, we need to count the number of &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; bits in its binary representation.
Naive Solution The naive solution for this problem would be to convert the binary number into a string and then simply iterate over the string and count the number of &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo;s. However, this solution is not optimal and is not taking advantage of the properties of binary numbers.
Algorithm The optimal solution for this problem involves using bitwise operation.</description></item><item><title>202. Happy Number</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/202/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/202/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement In this problem, we are given a number n. We have to determine whether this number is a &amp;ldquo;happy&amp;rdquo; number or not. A happy number is a number defined by the following process:
Starting with any positive integer, replace the number by the sum of the squares of its digits. Repeat the process until the number equals 1 (where it will stay), or it loops endlessly in a cycle which does not include 1. Those numbers for which this process ends in 1 are happy.</description></item><item><title>206. Reverse Linked List</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/206/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/206/</guid><description>LeetCode задача 206
Задача Дана голова односвязного списка. Задача состоит в том, чтобы развернуть этот список и вернуть его развернутую версию.
Подсказки В этой задаче нам нужно просто обойти односвязный список и изменить направление его указателей.
Подход Задача заключается в изменении направления указателей односвязного списка. Она может быть решена с помощью итеративного метода, при котором мы будем двигаться по списку, сохраняя предыдущий элемент, текущий и следующий. Затем мы просто изменим направление указателя next для текущего элемента, чтобы он указывал на предыдущий элемент.</description></item><item><title>234. Palindrome Linked List</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/234/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/234/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given the head of a singly linked list, return true if it is a palindrome or false otherwise.
Naive Solution A simple solution to this problem is to:
traverse the linked list storing the value of each node in an array. Then, we could compare the array with its reversed version.
If they match, the linked list is a palindrome. Otherwise, it is not.
This solution takes O(n) time (where n is the number of nodes in the list), as we need to traverse the list once.</description></item><item><title>283. Move Zeroes</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/283/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/283/</guid><description>LeetCode задача
Задача Дан целочисленный массив nums. Нам необходимо переместить все 0 в конец массива, сохраняя относительный порядок ненулевых элементов.
Примечание: вы должны сделать это на месте, без создания копии массива.
Подсказки Используйте два указателя: один будет указывать на текущий элемент, а другой будет указывать на первое место в массиве, куда можно поместить ненулевой элемент.
Подход Мы можем использовать два указателя: один для прохода по массиву и другой для отслеживания местоположения, куда следует поместить следующий ненулевой элемент. Этот метод позволяет нам сделать минимальное количество операций и изменений в массиве.</description></item><item><title>345. Reverse Vowels of a String</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/345/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/345/</guid><description>LeetCode задача 345
Задача Задана строка s. Необходимо перевернуть только гласные буквы в этой строке и вернуть результат.
Гласные буквы: 'a', 'e', 'i', 'o', 'u'. Они могут встречаться в верхнем и нижнем регистрах, и более одного раза.
Подсказки Для решения задачи можно использовать два указателя: один с начала строки, другой с конца. Затем можно двигаться этими указателями к центру строки, меняя местами гласные буквы.
Подход Используем два указателя для итерации по строке: один с начала (left), другой с конца (right).</description></item><item><title>392. Is Subsequence</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/392/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/392/</guid><description>LeetCode задача 392
Задача Даны две строки s и t. Верните true, если s является подпоследовательностью t, или false в противном случае.
Подпоследовательность строки - это новая строка, которая формируется из исходной строки путем удаления некоторых (может быть ни одного) символов без нарушения относительных позиций оставшихся символов. (например, &amp;ldquo;ace&amp;rdquo; является подпоследовательностью &amp;ldquo;abcde&amp;rdquo;, в то время как &amp;ldquo;aec&amp;rdquo; - нет).
Подсказки Следуя за обеими строками одновременно с помощью двух указателей, вы можете определить, является ли одна строка подпоследовательностью другой.</description></item><item><title>605. Can Place Flowers</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/605/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/605/</guid><description>LeetCode задача 605
Задача Дана длинная грядка, на которой некоторые участки уже засажены, а некоторые нет. Однако цветы нельзя сажать на соседние участки.
Подход Чтобы решить эту задачу, мы будем итерироваться по каждому участку грядки. Если участок пустой и его соседи (если они существуют) тоже пусты, мы сажаем цветок и уменьшаем наш счетчик.
Алгоритм Итерируемся по каждому участку грядки. Если участок пустой, проверяем его соседей. Если левый сосед пустой или его нет (начало грядки), проверяем правого соседа. Если правый сосед пустой или его нет (конец грядки), сажаем цветок на текущий участок и уменьшаем n.</description></item><item><title>643. Maximum Average Subarray I</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/643/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/643/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given an integer array nums consisting of n elements and an integer k, find a contiguous subarray whose length is equal to k that has the maximum average value and return this value. The result must be accurate up to a decimal point of 10^(-5).
Naive Solution A straightforward approach would be to calculate the average for every possible subarray of length k. For each starting point, sum the next k numbers and determine the average.</description></item><item><title>724. Find Pivot Index</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/724/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/724/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given an array of integers nums, the task is to calculate the pivot index of this array. The pivot index is defined as the index where the sum of all the numbers strictly to the left of the index is equal to the sum of all the numbers strictly to the index&amp;rsquo;s right. If no such index exists, return -1.
Naive Solution A naive approach would be to iterate over each index and for each index, calculate the sum of elements to the left and right of the index.</description></item><item><title>872. Leaf-Similar Trees</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/872/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/872/</guid><description>LeetCode задача 872
Задача Даны два бинарных дерева с корнями root1 и root2. Проверьте, являются ли эти деревья &amp;ldquo;листоподобными&amp;rdquo; (leaf-similar). Деревья считаются &amp;ldquo;листоподобными&amp;rdquo;, если последовательность листовых узлов каждого дерева одинакова.
Подсказки Листовые узлы бинарного дерева — это узлы, у которых нет потомков. Для проверки &amp;ldquo;листоподобности&amp;rdquo; двух деревьев нужно сравнить последовательности листовых узлов этих деревьев.
Подход / Идея решения Идея решения заключается в построении списков листовых узлов для каждого дерева, а затем сравнении этих списков. Мы можем рекурсивно обойти каждое дерево, проверяя при каждом узле, является ли он листовым.</description></item><item><title>933. Number of Recent Calls</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/933/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/933/</guid><description>LeetCode задача 933
Задача Реализуйте класс RecentCounter для подсчета вызовов ping за последние 3000 миллисекунд.
Т.е. для вызова t=100, нужно подсчитать количество таких вызовов, время которых меньше t-3000 и учесть сам вызов.
Подход В данной задаче нужно отслеживать количество вызовов ping за последние 3000 миллисекунд.
Можно использовать очередь для хранения времени вызовов ping. При каждом новом вызове будем добавлять текущее время в конец очереди и удалять из начала все времена, которые не попадают в интервал последних 3000 миллисекунд.</description></item><item><title>1071. Greatest Common Divisor of Strings</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1071/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1071/</guid><description>LeetCode задача 1071
Задача Для двух строк str1 и str2, вернуть наибольший общий делитель (НОД). Если такового не существует, вернуть пустую строку.
Подход Если строки str1 и str2 имеют НОД строки X, то str1 и str2 могут быть представлены в форме Xn и Xm (где n и m — это натуральные числа), соответственно. Это означает, что str1 должна начинаться с str2 или наоборот.
Алгоритм Проверка начала строк: если str1 не начинается с str2 или наоборот, то НОД не существует.</description></item><item><title>1207. Unique Number of Occurrences</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1207/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1207/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given an array of integers arr, return true if the number of occurrences of each value in the array is unique or false otherwise.
Naive Solution A naive approach would be to create a dictionary to store the count of each integer, then iterate over the dictionary and compare each count with the counts of other integers. This approach requires O(n^2) time complexity, where n is the length of the array. This is not efficient for large input sizes.</description></item><item><title>1337. The K Weakest Rows in a Matrix</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1337/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1337/</guid><description>LeetCode problem 1337
class Solution: def kWeakestRows(self, mat: List[List[int]], k: int) -&amp;gt; List[int]: m, n = len(mat), len(mat[0]) res = [n - bisect_right(row[::-1], 0) for row in mat] idx = list(range(m)) idx.sort(key=lambda i: res[i]) return idx[:k]</description></item><item><title>1732. Find the Highest Altitude</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1732/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1732/</guid><description>LeetCode задача 1732
Задача Велосипедист совершает путешествие, которое состоит из n + 1 точек на разных высотах. Путешествие начинается с точки 0, где высота равна 0.
Дан целочисленный массив gain длиной n, где gain[i] — это прирост высоты между точками i и i + 1 для всех (0 &amp;lt;= i &amp;lt; n).
Задача - вернуть самую высокую высоту точки.
Подход В этой задаче, вам нужно пройти по массиву gain и вычислить текущую высоту на каждом этапе. При этом следует отслеживать самую высокую высоту, которую вы достигли.</description></item><item><title>1768. Merge Strings Alternately</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1768/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1768/</guid><description>LeetCode задача 1768
Задача Вам даны две строки word1 и word2. Объедините эти строки, добавляя буквы в чередующем порядке, начиная с word1. Если одна строка длиннее другой, дополнительные буквы добавляются в конец результирующей строки.
Подход Чтобы решить эту задачу, мы можем использовать два указателя для каждого слова. Начнем с первого символа каждой строки и будем чередовать их, пока одна из строк не закончится. После этого, мы просто добавляем оставшиеся символы из более длинного слова к результирующей строке.
Алгоритм Инициализация результирующей строки и двух указателей для word1 и word2.</description></item><item><title>2108. Find First Palindromic String in the Array</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/2108/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/2108/</guid><description>LeetCode problem 2108
class Solution: def firstPalindrome(self, words: List[str]) -&amp;gt; str: return next((w for w in words if w == w[::-1]), &amp;#34;&amp;#34;)</description></item><item><title>2215. Find the Difference of Two Arrays</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/2215/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/2215/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given two 0-indexed integer arrays nums1 and nums2, return a list answer of size 2 where:
answer[0] is a list of all distinct integers in nums1 which are not present in nums2. answer[1] is a list of all distinct integers in nums2 which are not present in nums1. Note that the integers in the lists may be returned in any order.
Naive Solution A naive approach would be to iterate over each element of the first array and check whether it&amp;rsquo;s in the second array.</description></item><item><title>3028. Ant on the Boundary</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/3028/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/3028/</guid><description>LeetCode задача 3028
Воспользуемся функцией accumulate из модуля itertools, чтобы упростить вычисление и подсчет количества раз, когда муравей возвращается на границу, пройдя через массив nums.
Применяем функцию accumulate для подсчета накопительной суммы и подсчитываем количество раз, когда накопительная сумма равна 0.
Решение class Solution: def returnToBoundaryCount(self, nums: List[int]) -&amp;gt; int: return sum(s == 0 for s in accumulate(nums)) Функция accumulate(nums) генерирует последовательность накопленных сумм элементов массива nums, начиная с первого элемента.
Затем с помощью генераторного выражения s == 0 for s in accumulate(nums) мы создаем последовательность True и False, в зависимости от того, равна ли накопленная сумма в каждой точке нулю.</description></item><item><title>3032</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/3032/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/3032/</guid><description>https://leetcode.com/problems/count-numbers-with-unique-digits-ii
class Solution: def numberCount(self, a: int, b: int) -&amp;gt; int: # Initialize the count of numbers with all unique digits unique_digit_count = 0 # Loop through each number in the range from a to b, inclusive for num in range(a, b + 1): # Convert the number to a string to examine its digits num_str = str(num) # Convert the string to a set of characters to remove duplicates unique_digits = set(num_str) # If the length of the set is equal to the length of the number string, # it means all digits are unique if len(unique_digits) == len(num_str): # Increment the count for each number with all unique digits unique_digit_count += 1 # Return the total count of unique digit numbers return unique_digit_count</description></item><item><title/><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/3033/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/3033/</guid><description>class Solution: def modifiedMatrix(self, matrix: List[List[int]]) -&amp;gt; List[List[int]]: rows = len(matrix) cols = len(matrix[0]) for j in range(rows): max_val = max(matrix[i][j] for i in range(cols)) for i in range(cols): if matrix[i][j] == -1: matrix[i][j] = max_val return matrix</description></item></channel></rss>