<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AWS on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in AWS on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 &lt;a href="https://romankurnovskii.com">Roman Kurnovskii&lt;/a> personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS Certified Developer (DVA-C01 -> DVA-C02)</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/</guid><description>TL;DR Passed exam in one month. Created an app with questions and progress that helped me a lot Note The AWS Certified Developer - Associate exam is changing February 28, 2023. The last date to take the current exam is February 27, 2023.
To keep the docs up to date I will add new and latest information.
DVA-C01 vs DVA-C02 new domain: Domain 3: Deployment focus will be on testing and deploying your code into different environments including development, test, and production environments.</description></item><item><title>Configuring a Static Website With S3 And CloudFront</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/cloudfront/configuring-static-website-s3-and-cloudfront/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/cloudfront/configuring-static-website-s3-and-cloudfront/</guid><description>Practice Lab link Creating an Amazon S3 Bucket for a Static Website 1. In the AWS Management Console search bar, enter S3, and click the S3 result under Services:
You will be placed in the Amazon S3 console.
2. To start creating a new Amazon S3 bucket, in the top-right, click Create bucket:
The Amazon S3 bucket creation form will load.
3. Under General configuration, enter the following:
Bucket name: Enter _calabs-bucket-&amp;lt;UniqueNumber&amp;gt; _(Append a unique number to the end of calabs-bucket-) Region: Ensure US West (Oregon) us-west-2 is selected You have added a unique number to the bucket name because Amazon S3 bucket names must be unique regardless of the AWS region in which the bucket is created.</description></item><item><title>IAM</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/iam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/iam/</guid><description>About IAM - AWS Identity and Access Management
AWS IAM AWS IAM User Guide AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) allows to securely control user access to AWS services and resources.
Designed for organizations with multiple users or systems that use AWS products such as Amazon EC2, Amazon RDS, and AWS Management Console.
With IAM, you can centrally manage users, security credentials such as access keys, and permissions that control user access to AWS resources.</description></item><item><title>EC2</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/ec2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/ec2/</guid><description>About AWS EC2 AWS EC2 User Guide Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) - one of the most popular AWS services.
Allows:
to run different types of cloud instances and pay-per-use models. to control computing resources at the operating system level working in an Amazon computing environment. Digest EC2 &amp;amp; EBS EC2 (Elastic Compute Cloud) Instance EBS (Elastic Block Store) - Persistent storage volume AMI (Amazon Machine Image) - Packages OS and additional installations in a reusable template Instance and Instance Types: General Purpose (t-type and m-type), Compute Optimized(c-type), GPU Graphics, GPU Compute, Memory Optimized(r, × and z-type), and Storage Optimized(d, h and i-type) Purchasing Options: On Demand, Reserved, Scheduled, Spot, Dedicated Instance and Dedicated Host Spot: Partial hours are not billed if terminated by AWS EC2 Secure login information for your instances using key pairs Placement group: Cluster and Spread For root:</description></item><item><title>Elastic Beanstalk</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/elasticbeanstalk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/elasticbeanstalk/</guid><description>About AWS Elastic Beanstalk AWS Elastic Beanstalk User Guide AWS Elastic Beanstalk is an easy-to-use service for deploying and scaling web applications and services developed with Java, .NET, PHP, Node.js, Python, Ruby, Go, and Docker on familiar servers such as Apache, Nginx, Passenger, and IIS.
Deploying new application versions to existing resources in AWS Elastic Beanstalk happens much faster (typically under a minute) and once again is mostly dependent on the size of the new application version.</description></item><item><title>Lambda</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/lambda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/lambda/</guid><description>About AWS Lambda AWS Lambda User Guide AWS Lambda is a serverless computing service that runs program code in response to certain events and is responsible for automatically allocating the necessary computing resources.
AWS Lambda automatically runs program code in response to various events, such as HTTP requests through Amazon API Gateway, changing objects in Amazon Simple Storage Service garbage cans (Amazon S3), updating tables in Amazon DynamoDB or changing states in AWS Step Functions.</description></item><item><title>S3</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/</guid><description>About Amazon S3 (Simple Storage Service) provides object storage through a web service interface.
Amazon S3 Amazon S3 User Guide Price Pay only for what you use. There is no minimum charge.
Price
S3 | EFS | EBS Amazon S3 is an object storage designed for storing large numbers of user files and backups. Good for storing backups and other static data Can be publicly accessible Web interface Object Storage Scalable Slower than EBS and EFS Amazon EBS (Amazon Elastic Block Store) is block storage for Amazon EC2 compute instances - it is similar to hard drives attached to your computers or laptops, but in a virtualized environment.</description></item><item><title>DynamoDB</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/dynamodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/dynamodb/</guid><description>About Fast and flexible NoSQL database service for performance with millisecond latency at any scale
Amazon DynamoDB documentation Developer Guide Pricing Amazon DynamoDB pricing
When you use the DynamoDB service, you are charged for reading, writing, and storing data in DynamoDB tables, as well as any additional features you enable. DynamoDB supports two resource provisioning modes that correspond to specific billing schemes for processing read and write operations on your tables: on-demand and with preparation. Click the following links to learn more about the billing options for each provisioning mode</description></item><item><title>ElastiCache</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/elasticache/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/elasticache/</guid><description>About Documentation User Guide Amazon Elasticache is a fully managed Redis or Memcached in-memory data store.
It&amp;rsquo;s great for use cases like two-tier web applications where the most frequently accesses data is stored in ElastiCache so response time is optimal.
You can use ElastiCache for caching, which accelerates application and database performance, or as a primary data store for use cases that don&amp;rsquo;t require durability like session stores, gaming leaderboards, streaming, and analytics.
Compatible with Redis and Memcached</description></item><item><title>RDS</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/rds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/rds/</guid><description>About Relational Database Service Managed DB service that uses SQL as query language Amazon Relational Database Service (Amazon RDS) is a collection of managed services that makes it simple to set up, operate, and scale databases in the cloud.
Documentation User Guide Supports engines:
Amazon Aurora with MySQL compatibility: 5432 Amazon Aurora with PostgreSQL compatibility: 5432 MySQL: 3306 MariaDB: 3306 PostgreSQL: 5432 Oracle: 1521 SQL Server: 1433 Engine modes:
Used in CreateDBCluster
global parallelquery serverless multimaster Backups Backups are enabled by default in RDS Automated backups</description></item><item><title>API Gateway</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/api-gateway/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/api-gateway/</guid><description>About Documentation User Guide API Gateway provides the opportunity to create and expand your own REST and WebSocket APIs at any size.
API endpoints can be cached to accommodate for frequent similar requests.
Use Cases Build a network for micros­ervices archit­ectures.
Amazon CloudWatch metrics - Collects near-real-time metrics Examples: 4XXError (client-side errors), 5XXError(server-side errors), CacheHitCount Amazon CloudWatch Logs - Debug issues related to request execution AWS CloudTrail - Record of actions taken by a user, role, or an AWS service in API Gateway AWS X-Ray - Trace your request across different AWS Services Digests Concepts REST API, HTTP API, WebSocket API</description></item><item><title>CloudFront</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/cloudfront/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/cloudfront/</guid><description>About Securely deliver data, videos, applic­ations, and APIs to customers globally with low latency, and high transfer speeds
CloudFront is a distributed content delivery network (CDN) that enables easy delivery of web content to end users from a pool of web servers around the globe
Documentation User Guide CloudFront is a global service:
Ingress to upload objects. Egress to distribute content. Terminology Edge Location: The location where content is cached to be accessed by users. These are READ/WRITE.</description></item><item><title>Elastic Load Balancing</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/elasticloadbalancing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/elasticloadbalancing/</guid><description>About Elastic Load Balancing (ELB) automa­tically distri­butes incoming applic­ation traffic across multiple targets, such as EC2&amp;rsquo;s, contai­ners, IP addresses, &amp;amp; Lambda functions.
Elastic Load Balancing is a best practice to assign incoming traffic to a single target, such as an EC2 Instance, and then distribute the rest of the traffic across the target&amp;rsquo;s resources. An elastic load balancer distributes traffic across an arbitrary number of targets.
Documentation User Guide Types of Load Balancers Type Description Application Load Balancer (ALB) Operates at the Application Layer (OSI L7), handling HTTP/HTTPS traffic.</description></item><item><title>Kinesis</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/kinesis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/kinesis/</guid><description>About Kinesis makes it easy to collect, process, &amp;amp; analyze real-time, streaming data, so one can get timely insights.
Documentation User Guide Amazon Kinesis enables you to process and analyze data as it arrives and respond instantly instead of having to wait until all your data is collected before the processing can begin.
Real-time-based Fully managed Scalable Capabilities Kinesis Video Streams Capture, process, and store video streams Kinesis Data Streams Capture, process, and store data streams Kinesis Data Firehose Load data streams into AWS data stores</description></item><item><title>OpenSearch Service</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/opensearch-service/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/opensearch-service/</guid><description>About OpenSearch Service is a fully managed service that makes it easy to deploy, secure
Amazon OpenSearch Service is an open source, distributed search and analytics suite based on Elasticsearch.
Documentation User Guide You can load streaming data from the following sources using AWS Lambda event handlers:
Amazon S3 Amazon Kinesis Data Streams and Data Firehose Amazon DynamoDB Amazon CloudWatch AWS IoT Exposes three Elasticsearch logs through CloudWatch Logs:
error logs. search slow logs – These logs help fine tune the performance of any kind of search operation on Elasticsearch.</description></item><item><title>CloudWatch</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/cloudwatch/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/cloudwatch/</guid><description>About CloudWatch offers a reliable, scalable, &amp;amp; flexible monitoring solution that can easily start.
CloudWatch can provide a dependable, scalable, &amp;amp; flexible monitoring solution that is simple to set up.
Documentation User Guide CloudWatch vs CloudTrail CloudWatch CloudTrail Performance monitoring Auditing Log events across AWS Services – think operations Log API activity across AWS services – think activities, or who to blame Higher-level comprehensive monitoring and event service More low-level, granular Log from multiple accounts Log from multiple accounts Logs stored indefinitely Logs stored to S3 or CloudWatch indefinitely Alarms history for 14 days No native alarming; can use CloudWatch alarms Digest Standard vs High resolution metrics.</description></item><item><title>CloudFormation</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/cloudformation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/cloudformation/</guid><description>About CloudF­orm­ation enables the user to design &amp;amp; provision AWS infras­tru­cture deploy­ments predic­tably &amp;amp; repeat­edly
Documentation User Guide Terminology Component Description Templates The JSON or YAML text file that contains the instructions for building out the AWS environment Stacks The entire environment described by the template and created, updated, and deleted as a single unit StackSets AWS CloudFormation StackSets extends the functionality of stacks by enabling you to create, update, or delete stacks across multiple accounts and regions with a single operation Change Sets A summary of proposed changes to your stack that will allow you to see how those changes might impact your existing resources before implementing them Template The main sections in a CloudFormation template:</description></item><item><title>CodeCommit</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codecommit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codecommit/</guid><description>About CodeCommit is a version control service (Git repository service) that enables the user to personally store &amp;amp; manage Git archives in the AWS cloud.
Documentation User Guide CodeCommit is integrated with Jenkins, CodeBuild and other CI tools.
Price 5 active users free per month with the
Current price
Practice Introduction to CodeCommit</description></item><item><title>CodeDeploy</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codedeploy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codedeploy/</guid><description>About CodeDeploy is a fully managed deployment service that automates software deploy­ments to a variety of compute services such as EC2, Fargate, Lambda, &amp;amp; on-pre­mises servers
Documentation User Guide CodeDeploy can also deploy a serverless Lambda function.
CodeDeploy can be connected to CodePipeline and use artifacts from there.
Platforms Need to choose the compute platform:
EC2/On-premises. AWS Lambda. Amazon ECS. AppSpec File The application specification file (AppSpec file) is a YAML-formatted, or JSON-formatted file used by CodeDeploy to manage a deployment.</description></item><item><title>CodeBuild</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codebuild/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codebuild/</guid><description>About CodeBuild is a fully managed service that assembles source code, runs unit tests, &amp;amp; also generates artefacts ready to deploy.
Documentation User Guide CodeBuild is a code creation service that also produces code artefacts upon request.
CodeBuild is an alternative to other build tools such as Jenkins.
CodeBuild is integrated with KMS for encryption of build artifacts, IAM for build permissions, VPC for network security, and CloudTrail for logging API calls.
CodeBuild is a fully managed build service to compile source code, run unit tests and produce artifacts that are ready for deployment.</description></item><item><title>CodePipeline</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codepipeline/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codepipeline/</guid><description>About AWS CodePipeline is a fully managed continuous delivery service that helps you automate your release pipelines for fast and reliable application and infrastructure updates.
Documentation User Guide CodePipeline automates the build, test, and deploy phases of your release process every time there is a code change, based on the release model you define.
You can easily integrate AWS CodePipeline with third-party services such as GitHub or with your own custom plugin. With AWS CodePipeline, you only pay for what you use.</description></item><item><title>CodeGuru</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codeguru/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codeguru/</guid><description>About Amazon CodeGuru is a developer tool that provides intelligent recommendations to improve code quality and identify an application’s most expensive lines of code.
CodeGuru is a developer tool powered by machine learning that provides intell­igent recomm­end­ations for improving code quality &amp;amp; identi­fying an applic­ation’s most expensive lines of code.
Documentation User Guide Amazon CodeGuru is comprised of two services: CoduGuru Reviewer and CodeGuru Profiler. Reviewer is what listens for pull requests in a repository and reviews code changes.</description></item><item><title>CodeStar</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codestar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codestar/</guid><description>About AWS CodeStar enables you to quickly develop, build, and deploy applications on AWS. AWS CodeStar provides a unified user interface, enabling you to easily manage your software development activities in one place.
Documentation User Guide CodeStar enables to quickly develop, build, &amp;amp; deploy applic­ations on AWS.
With AWS CodeStar, you can create, manage, and scale automated code reviews with a single click. You can also monitor the performance and scalability of your code review process with the built-in metrics dashboard.</description></item><item><title>CodeArtifact</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codeartifact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/codeartifact/</guid><description>About AWS CodeArtifact is a fully managed artifact repository service that makes it easy for organizations of any size to securely store, publish, and share software packages used in their software development process.
Documentation User Guide CodeAr­tifact is a secure storage, publishing, and sharing of software code packages used in a development process organisation&amp;rsquo;s software development. CodeAr­tifact makes it easy for small organisations to store, publish, and share software packages.
CodeArtifact can be configured to automatically fetch software packages and dependencies from public artifact repositories.</description></item><item><title>X-Ray</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/xray/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/xray/</guid><description>About AWS X-Ray helps developers analyze and debug production, distributed applications, such as those built using a microservices architecture.
Documentation User Guide X-Ray allows software engineers to view the state of a system at a glance, identify potential bottlenecks, and make informed operational decisions to improve performance and reliability. X-Ray inspects application code using a combination of machine and customer-provided data to identify potential bottlenecks and analyze performance and performance trends for each test scenario.</description></item><item><title>Fault Injection Simulator</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/fis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/fis/</guid><description>About AWS Fault Injection Simulator (FIS) is a fully managed service for running fault injection experiments on AWS that makes it easier to improve an application’s performance, observability, and resiliency.
Documentation User Guide Price Current price
With AWS FIS, you pay only for what you use. There are no upfront costs or minimum fees. You are charged based on the duration that an action is active. The AWS FIS price is $0.10 per action-minute.
Terminology and Concepts Everything starts with an experiment template.</description></item><item><title>Elastic Container Registry</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/ecr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/ecr/</guid><description>About Amazon Elastic Container Registry (Amazon ECR) - Fully managed container registry offering high-performance hosting, so you can reliably deploy application images and artifacts anywhere
Documentation User Guide Hosted private Docker registry
Alternatives Docker Hub JFrog Artifactory Azure Container Registry Harbor Google Container Registry Red Hat Quay JFrog Container Registry Price Current price
Use Cases Store, encrypt, and manage container images
Manage software vulnerabilities Streamline your deployment workloads Manage image lifecycle policies Type: Containers
Same type services: Elastic Container Service (ECS), Elastic Container Registry (ECR), Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS), Fargate</description></item><item><title>Elastic Container Service</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/ecs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/ecs/</guid><description>About Documentation User Guide Highly secure, reliable, &amp;amp; scalable way to run contai­ners
Alternatives Google Container Engine (GKE) Azure Container Service IBM Bluemix Container Service Jelastic Multi-Cloud PaaS Terminology Amazon ECS Term Definition Cluster Logical Grouping of EC2 Instances Container Instance EC2 instance running the ECS agent Task Definition Blueprint that describes how a docker container should launch Task A running container using settings in a Task Definition Service Defines long running tasks – can control task count with Auto Scaling and attach an ELB Digest Microservices are built in multiple programming languages Containers simplify deployment of microservices: Step 1 : Create a self contained Docker image Application Runtime (JDK or Python), Application code and Dependencies Step 2 : Run it as a container any where Local machine OR Corporate data center OR Cloud Use On-Demand instances or Spot instances Launch type: EC2 or Fargate Data volumes attached to containers Deployment type: Rolling update Blue/green deployment (powered by AWS CodeDeploy) Task Placement Strategies: binpack - Leave least amount of unused CPU or memory.</description></item><item><title>Fargate</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/fargate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/fargate/</guid><description>About Serverless version of ECS.
Serverless compute for contai­ners.
AWS Fargate is a serverless, pay-as-you-go compute engine that lets you focus on building applications without managing servers.
Deploy and manage your applications, not infrastructure. Fargate removes the operational overhead of scaling, patching, securing, and managing servers.
Compatible with both Amazon Elastic Container Service (ECS) and Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS).
Documentation User Guide Alternatives Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE) Red Hat OpenShift Container Platform Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) Rancher Azure Container Instances Cloud Foundry Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Container Engine for Kubernetes Price Current price</description></item><item><title>Elastic Kubernetes Service</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/eks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/eks/</guid><description>About Kubernetes (K8) Docker Container/Cluster management
Run highly secure, reliable, and scalable containers
Documentation User Guide Alternatives Red Hat OpenShift Container Platform Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) Rancher Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE) Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Container Engine for Kubernetes Mirantis Kubernetes Engine (formerly Docker Enterprise) Kubernetes Cloud Foundry Price Current price
Use Cases Build and run web applications Deploy across hybrid environments Model machine learning (ML) workflows ECS vs EKS Amazon provides the Elastic Container Service for Kubernetes (Amazon EKS) which can be used to deploy, manage, and scale containerized applications using Kubernetes on AWS.</description></item><item><title>Cognito</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/cognito/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/cognito/</guid><description>About Amazon Cognito - Simple and Secure User Sign-Up, Sign-In, and Access Control
Documentation User Guide Amazon Cognito lets you add user sign-up, sign-in, and access control to your web and mobile apps quickly and easily. Amazon Cognito scales to millions of users and supports sign-in with social identity providers, such as Apple, Facebook, Google, and Amazon, and enterprise identity providers via SAML 2.0 and OpenID Connect.
Users can sign in directly with a user name and password, or through a third party such as Facebook, Amazon, or Google.</description></item><item><title>Route 53</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/route53/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/route53/</guid><description>About Amazon Route 53 is a highly available and scalable Domain Name System (DNS) web service. Route 53 connects user requests to internet applications running on AWS or on-premises.
Documentation User Guide A highly available and scalable Domain Name System (DNS) web service used for domain registration, DNS routing, and health checking.
Can create and manage your public DNS records.
What is the difference between Route 53 and DNS?
Your DNS is the service that translates your domain name into an IP address.</description></item><item><title>Key Management Service</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/kms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/kms/</guid><description>About AWS Key Management Service (KMS) makes it easy for you to create and manage cryptographic keys and control their use across a wide range of AWS services and in your applications.
Documentation User Guide AWS KMS provides management of encryption keys for use with other AWS services (e.g. EBS, S3, RDS, etc.).
Key management on AWS is a broad range of activities from creating &amp;amp; storing public &amp;amp; private keys to creating, managing, and authorising access to AWS services with digital keys.</description></item><item><title>EventBridge</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/eventbridge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/eventbridge/</guid><description>About EventB­ridge is a serverless event bus that makes it easy to connect applic­ations together using data from apps, integrated SaaS apps, &amp;amp; AWS services.
Documentation User Guide EventB­ridge is a low-cost alternative to building a new backend infrastructure for every new app. With Serverless EventB­ridge, you can connect your existing apps with a few lines of code. You don’t have to build a new backend for every new app you want to connect to.</description></item><item><title>Simple Notification Service</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/sns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/sns/</guid><description>About Amazon Simple Notification Service (Amazon SNS) is a fully managed messaging service for both application-to-application (A2A) and application-to-person (A2P) communication.
Documentation User Guide SNS is a fully managed messaging service for both system­-to­-system &amp;amp; app-to­-person (A2P) commun­ica­tion.
Amazon SNS can also send notifications via SMS text message, email, SQS queues or to any HTTP endpoint.
Amazon SNS notifications can also trigger Lambda functions.
Amazon SNS is inexpensive and based on a pay-as-you-go model with no upfront costs.</description></item><item><title>Simple Queue Service</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/sqs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/sqs/</guid><description>About Fully managed message queues for microservices, distributed systems, and serverless applications
Documentation User Guide SQS offers two types of message queues. Standard queues offer maximum throughput, best-effort ordering, and at-least-once delivery. SQS FIFO queues are designed to guarantee that messages are processed exactly once, in the exact order that they are sent.
SQS is a fully managed message queuing service that enables to decouple &amp;amp; scale micros­erv­ices, distri­buted systems, &amp;amp; serverless applic­ations.
Messages are published to an Amazon SNS topic and then pushed to Amazon SQS subscriber queues.</description></item><item><title>Step Functions</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/step-functions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/step-functions/</guid><description>About AWS Step Functions is a low-code, visual workflow service that developers use to build distributed applications, automate IT and business processes, and build data and machine learning pipelines using AWS services.
Documentation User Guide Step Functions is a serverless function orches­trator that makes it easy to sequence Lambda functions &amp;amp; multiple AWS services into busine­ss-­cri­tical applic­ations.
Alternatives AWS lambda Airflow Google Cloud Workflows Microsoft Flow Price Pay only for what you use
Current price</description></item><item><title>Serverless: Flask+API Gateway+Lambda+MongoDB</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/serverless-flask-lambda-api-gateway-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/serverless-flask-lambda-api-gateway-mongodb/</guid><description>mongodb free tier vs documentdb
Project structure - src - app.py - mongo.py - .env - requirements.txt - serverless.yml Sources
Add AIM user Setup specific user for serverless deployment
username: serverless-deployer
aws aim documentation Set policy Create:
ServerLessDeployerPolicyGroup ServerLessDeployerPolicy Policy:
{ &amp;#34;Statement&amp;#34;: [ { &amp;#34;Action&amp;#34;: [ &amp;#34;apigateway:*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:CancelUpdateStack&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:ContinueUpdateRollback&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:CreateChangeSet&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:CreateStack&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:CreateUploadBucket&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:DeleteStack&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:Describe*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:EstimateTemplateCost&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:ExecuteChangeSet&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:Get*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:List*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:UpdateStack&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:UpdateTerminationProtection&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;cloudformation:ValidateTemplate&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;dynamodb:CreateTable&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;dynamodb:DeleteTable&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;dynamodb:DescribeTable&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;dynamodb:DescribeTimeToLive&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;dynamodb:UpdateTimeToLive&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:AttachInternetGateway&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:AuthorizeSecurityGroupIngress&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:CreateInternetGateway&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:CreateNetworkAcl&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:CreateNetworkAclEntry&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:CreateRouteTable&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:CreateSecurityGroup&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:CreateSubnet&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:CreateTags&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:CreateVpc&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:DeleteInternetGateway&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:DeleteNetworkAcl&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:DeleteNetworkAclEntry&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:DeleteRouteTable&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:DeleteSecurityGroup&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:DeleteSubnet&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:DeleteVpc&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:Describe*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:DetachInternetGateway&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ec2:ModifyVpcAttribute&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;events:DeleteRule&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;events:DescribeRule&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;events:ListRuleNamesByTarget&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;events:ListRules&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;events:ListTargetsByRule&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;events:PutRule&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;events:PutTargets&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;events:RemoveTargets&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iam:AttachRolePolicy&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iam:CreateRole&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iam:DeleteRole&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iam:DeleteRolePolicy&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iam:DetachRolePolicy&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iam:GetRole&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iam:PassRole&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iam:PutRolePolicy&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iot:CreateTopicRule&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iot:DeleteTopicRule&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iot:DisableTopicRule&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iot:EnableTopicRule&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iot:ReplaceTopicRule&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;kinesis:CreateStream&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;kinesis:DeleteStream&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;kinesis:DescribeStream&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;lambda:*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;logs:CreateLogDelivery&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;logs:CreateLogGroup&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;logs:DeleteLogGroup&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;logs:DescribeLogGroups&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;logs:DescribeLogStreams&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;logs:FilterLogEvents&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;logs:GetLogEvents&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;logs:PutSubscriptionFilter&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:CreateBucket&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:DeleteBucket&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:DeleteBucketPolicy&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:DeleteObject&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:DeleteObjectVersion&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:GetObject&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:GetObjectVersion&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:ListAllMyBuckets&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:ListBucket&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:PutBucketNotification&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:PutBucketPolicy&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:PutBucketTagging&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:PutBucketWebsite&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:PutEncryptionConfiguration&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:PutObject&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;sns:CreateTopic&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;sns:DeleteTopic&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;sns:GetSubscriptionAttributes&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;sns:GetTopicAttributes&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;sns:ListSubscriptions&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;sns:ListSubscriptionsByTopic&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;sns:ListTopics&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;sns:SetSubscriptionAttributes&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;sns:SetTopicAttributes&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;sns:Subscribe&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;sns:Unsubscribe&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;states:CreateStateMachine&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;states:DeleteStateMachine&amp;#34; ], &amp;#34;Effect&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Allow&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Resource&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;*&amp;#34; } ], &amp;#34;Version&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;2012-10-17&amp;#34; } Create user copy the API Key &amp;amp; Secret</description></item><item><title>Introduction to DynamoDB</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/dynamodb/introduction-dynamodb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/dynamodb/introduction-dynamodb/</guid><description>Lab
Creating a DynamoDB Table with a Partition Key 1. From the AWS Management Console, in the search bar at the top, enter DynamoDB, and under Services, click the DynamoDB result:
The Amazon DynamoDB product overview page will load.
2. To start creating a new DyanmoDB table, on the right-hand side, click Create table:
3. In the Table details section, enter the following:
Table Name: Partition Key: Enter Name and ensure type is 4. In the Settings section, select Customize settings:</description></item><item><title>AWS Amplify - project setup with Github</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/cloud-exam-quizz/amplify-setup-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/cloud-exam-quizz/amplify-setup-project/</guid><description>Preface For Amplify project I use eu-west region github repo has to be ready private or public New project goto https://eu-west-1.console.aws.amazon.com/amplify/home?region=eu-west-1#/
New app → Host web app → Github
Add access to github repo Select repository Come back to Amplify and try again to choose repo Click Next
Update amplify.yml for node.js project
version: 1 frontend: phases: preBuild: commands: - yarn install build: commands: - yarn run build artifacts: baseDirectory: build files: - &amp;#39;**/*&amp;#39; cache: paths: - node_modules/**/* Next → Save and deploy Amplify starts to build project and generates project url.</description></item><item><title>AWS Amplify - Set custom domain</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/cloud-exam-quizz/amplify-custom-domain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/cloud-exam-quizz/amplify-custom-domain/</guid><description>You can use any custom domain with Amplify and no need register it with AWS Route53.
I am adding domain at the setup app stage. Another way is from console.
Click Domain management. or
Add domain Write domain name -&amp;gt; Configure domain -&amp;gt; Save Nest starts SSL configuration process. Amplify provides with DNS data that you need to write in the domain register account. Once SSL creation starts you can get domain data
Action -&amp;gt; View DNS records</description></item></channel></rss>