<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Strings on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/strings/</link><description>Recent content in Strings on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/strings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>443. String Compression</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/443/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/443/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given a list of characters, chars, you are required to compress the list using the following algorithm:
Start with an empty string, s. For each group of consecutive repeating characters in chars: If the group&amp;rsquo;s length is 1, append the character to s. Otherwise, append the character followed by the group&amp;rsquo;s length. The compressed string s should be stored back in the chars list. The length of the group that is 10 or longer will be split into multiple characters in chars.</description></item><item><title>1657. Determine if Two Strings Are Close</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1657/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1657/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Two strings are considered close if you can attain one from the other using two operations:
Swap any two existing characters. Transform every occurrence of one existing character into another existing character, and do the same with the other character. The challenge is to determine whether two given strings are close or not.
Naive Solution A naive approach might involve trying every possible combination of operations on the two strings until they match or until you&amp;rsquo;ve exhausted all possibilities.</description></item></channel></rss>