<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>nmap - cheatsheet</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/nmap-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/nmap-cheatsheet/</guid><description>Scanning Options Nmap Option Description 10.10.10.0/24 Target network range. -sn Disables port scanning. -Pn Disables ICMP Echo Requests -n Disables DNS Resolution. -PE Performs the ping scan by using ICMP Echo Requests against the target. --packet-trace Shows all packets sent and received. --reason Displays the reason for a specific result. --disable-arp-ping Disables ARP Ping Requests. --top-ports=&amp;lt;num&amp;gt; Scans the specified top ports that have been defined as most frequent. -p- Scan all ports. -p22-110 Scan all ports between 22 and 110.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/debian-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/debian-setup/</guid><description>Auditing Packages dpkg --verify or
dpkg -V # dpkg -V ??5?????? /lib/systemd/system/ssh.service ??5?????? c /etc/libvirt/qemu/networks/default.xml &amp;lsquo;ssh.service&amp;rsquo;: reports a change to SSH&amp;rsquo;s service file that the administrator made to the packaged file instead of using an appropriate /etc/systemd/system/ssh.service override &amp;lsquo;c&amp;rsquo; letter: legitimately modified Monitoring Files AIDE apt install aide aideinit # first db init aideinit creates a cron job in etc/cron.daily/aide
DB: /var/lib/aide/aide.db
When changes are detected, AIDE records them in log files /var/log/aide/*.log
logcheck Monitors log files every hour by default and sends unusual log messages in emails to the administrator for further analysis</description></item><item><title>Wireless access point with hostapd on Debian</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/wireless-access-point/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/wireless-access-point/</guid><description>Configure network traffic routing and Network Address Translation (NAT) using iptables.
Configure the system to forward packets from one network interface to another, applying NAT to the packets going out of the eth0 interface.
Network configuration where the system is intended to function as a router or gateway between two networks (e.g., forwarding packets from a Wi-Fi network to an Ethernet network).
kali@kali:~$ sudo iptables -t nat -F kali@kali:~$ kali@kali:~$ sudo iptables -F kali@kali:~$ kali@kali:~$ sudo iptables -t nat -A POSTROUTING -o eth0 -j MASQUERADE kali@kali:~$ kali@kali:~$ sudo iptables -A FORWARD -i wlan0 -o eth0 -j ACCEPT kali@kali:~$ kali@kali:~$ echo 1 | sudo tee /proc/sys/net/ipv4/ip_forward # (DNS, dhcp still required) kali@kali:~$ 1.</description></item><item><title>How to disable IPv6 on Debian/Kali Linux</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/howto-disable-ipv6-on-debian/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/howto-disable-ipv6-on-debian/</guid><description>TL;DR git clone https://github.com/romankurnovskii/kali-shortcuts.git cd kali-shortcuts chmod +x disable_ipv6.sh sudo ./disable_ipv6.sh Edit sysctl Configuration In the terminal, type sudo vi /etc/sysctl.conf and press Enter. This opens the sysctl.conf file in the text editor with root privileges. Add IPv6 Disable Lines At the end of the file, add the following lines: net.ipv6.conf.all.disable_ipv6 = 1 net.ipv6.conf.default.disable_ipv6 = 1 net.ipv6.conf.lo.disable_ipv6 = 1 These lines will disable IPv6 on all network interfaces, including the loopback interface.
Save and Exit Save /etc/sysctl.conf and exit text editor Apply Changes To apply the changes without rebooting, run `sudo sysctl -p`` in the terminal.</description></item><item><title>Interactive vs. Non-Interactive Users in Linux</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux-interactive-non-interactive-users/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux-interactive-non-interactive-users/</guid><description>Characteristics In a Linux environment, users can be broadly categorized as &amp;ldquo;interactive&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;non-interactive&amp;rdquo;. These distinctions stem from how these user accounts interact (or don&amp;rsquo;t interact) with the system.
Definition Interactive Users: These are users who interact directly with the system, usually through a shell. When you log into a computer using SSH or a terminal, you&amp;rsquo;re operating as an interactive user. Non-Interactive Users: These users are designed to perform specific tasks without direct human intervention. Examples include system accounts running services like apache or mysql.</description></item><item><title>Bash Special Variables $! $0 $? $$</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/bash-variables/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/bash-variables/</guid><description>$0 - The Name of the Script $0 represents the name of the Bash script as it was called.
If you execute a script with bash myscript.sh, then within myscript.sh, $0 will be myscript.sh.
$1, $2, $3, &amp;hellip; - Positional Parameters These variables correspond to the arguments passed to the script. $1 is the first argument, $2 is the second, and so on.
In the command bash myscript.sh arg1 arg2, $1 equals arg1, and $2 equals arg2.
$! - PID of the Last Background Process This holds the process ID of the most recent background process.</description></item><item><title>Bash code snippets</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/bash-snippets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/bash-snippets/</guid><description>Rename all files by pattern in current directory files=(*) for file in &amp;#34;${files[@]}&amp;#34; do # Check if the file name contains the &amp;#34;№&amp;#34; symbol if [[ $file == *&amp;#34;№&amp;#34;* ]]; then # Remove everything before and including the &amp;#34;№&amp;#34; symbol new_file=${file##*&amp;#34;№&amp;#34;} mv &amp;#34;$file&amp;#34; &amp;#34;$new_file&amp;#34; echo &amp;#34;Renamed $file to $new_file&amp;#34; fi done Add substring to filename #!/bin/bash DIR=&amp;#34;/path/to/folder&amp;#34; cd &amp;#34;$DIR&amp;#34; # Rename all .png files and add &amp;#34;.ru&amp;#34; before .png for file in *.png; do base=$(basename &amp;#34;$file&amp;#34; .png) mv &amp;#34;$file&amp;#34; &amp;#34;${base}.</description></item><item><title>How to Download and Install Linux RHEL 9 for Free</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/howto-install-rhel-9-free/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/howto-install-rhel-9-free/</guid><description>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 9 (RHEL 9), codenamed Plow, has gone public (GA). Red Hat announced it on May 18, 2022. It replaced the beta version, which had been in existence since November 3, 2021.
RHEL 9 is the first few releases in the Red Hat family. It is the first major release since IBM acquired Red Hat in July 2019, and the first major release since abandoning the CentOS project in favor of CentOS Stream, which is now RHEL&amp;rsquo;s predecessor.</description></item><item><title>Tar command Cheat Sheet</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/cheat-sheet-command-tar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/cheat-sheet-command-tar/</guid><description>Common options z compress with gzip c create an archive u append files which are newer than the corresponding copy ibn the archive f filename of the archive v verbose, display what is inflated or deflated a unlike of z, determine compression based on file extension Create tar named archive.tar containing directory tar cf archive.tar /path/files Concatenate files into a single tar tar -cf archive.tar /path/files Extract the contents from archive.tar tar xf archive.tar Create a gzip compressed tar file name archive.</description></item></channel></rss>