<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SlidingWindow on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tags/slidingwindow/</link><description>Recent content in SlidingWindow on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>ru</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tags/slidingwindow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1456. Maximum Number of Vowels in a Substring of Given Length</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1456/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1456/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem 1456
Problem Statement Given a string s and an integer k, the task is to return the maximum number of vowel letters in any substring of s with length k.
Vowel letters in English are &amp;lsquo;a&amp;rsquo;, &amp;rsquo;e&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;i&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;o&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;u&amp;rsquo;.
Naive Solution The most straightforward solution to this problem is to take every possible substring of length k and count the number of vowels in each of them. This can be done using nested loops. The outer loop runs through each character in the string while the inner loop counts the vowels for each substring of length k.</description></item><item><title>1493. Longest Subarray of 1's After Deleting One Element</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1493/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1493/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem 1493
Problem Statement Given a binary array nums, you should delete one element from it. The goal is to return the size of the longest subarray containing only 1&amp;rsquo;s after this deletion. If no such subarray exists, return 0.
Naive Solution A straightforward approach is to manually try deleting each element in the array and checking the length of the longest sequence of 1&amp;rsquo;s. This would involve nested loops: an outer loop for deleting an element and an inner loop to check sequences of 1&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item></channel></rss>