<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Algorithms on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/algorithms/</link><description>Recent content in Algorithms on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/algorithms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>152. Maximum Product Subarray</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/152/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/152/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement In this problem, we&amp;rsquo;re given an integer array nums, and our task is to find the maximum product of a contiguous subarray. A subarray is a contiguous part of an array. The interesting part of this problem is that the array can contain both positive and negative numbers, so the maximum product can be obtained by a subarray ending at any index of the array.
Naive Solution A naive approach to this problem would be to calculate the product of all possible subarrays and return the maximum one.</description></item><item><title>189. Rotate Array</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/189/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/189/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given an integer array nums, rotate the array to the right by k steps, where k is non-negative.
Naive Solution A simple, but inefficient, approach would be to rotate the array k times. In each rotation, we shift every element of the array to the right by one and move the last element to the start of the array. This solution has a time complexity of O(n*k), where n is the number of elements in the array and k is the number of rotations.</description></item><item><title>202. Happy Number</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/202/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/202/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement In this problem, we are given a number n. We have to determine whether this number is a &amp;ldquo;happy&amp;rdquo; number or not. A happy number is a number defined by the following process:
Starting with any positive integer, replace the number by the sum of the squares of its digits. Repeat the process until the number equals 1 (where it will stay), or it loops endlessly in a cycle which does not include 1. Those numbers for which this process ends in 1 are happy.</description></item><item><title>206. Reverse Linked List</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/206/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/206/</guid><description>LeetCode problem 206
Problem Statement Reverse a given singly linked list and return its head. A singly linked list is a data structure consisting of nodes, where each node has a value and a reference to the next node in the sequence.
Naive Solution A naive approach could be to traverse the entire linked list once to read all its elements into an array. Then, we could reverse the array and construct a new linked list from it. This would work, but it takes up additional space for the array.</description></item><item><title>394. Decode String</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/394/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/394/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given an encoded string, the task is to decode it to produce a string. The encoding rule is: k[encoded_string], where the encoded_string inside the square brackets is being repeated exactly k times.
Naive Solution A naive approach would be to repeatedly look for a pattern in the string where there is a number followed by square brackets. For each such pattern found, replace it with the string inside the square brackets repeated &amp;lsquo;k&amp;rsquo; times. This would work but might not be the most efficient solution, especially for nested brackets.</description></item><item><title>605. Can Place Flowers</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/605/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/605/</guid><description>LeetCode problem 605
In this problem, we are given a flowerbed represented by an integer array flowerbed, where 0 represents an empty plot and 1 represents a plot with a flower.
We need to determine if we can plant n new flowers in the flowerbed without violating the rule that no two adjacent plots can have flowers.
Naive Solution To solve this problem, we can use a greedy approach. We iterate through the flowerbed and check each plot. If a plot is empty and its adjacent plots are also empty, we can plant a flower in that plot.</description></item><item><title>643. Maximum Average Subarray I</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/643/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/643/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given an integer array nums consisting of n elements and an integer k, find a contiguous subarray whose length is equal to k that has the maximum average value and return this value. The result must be accurate up to a decimal point of 10^(-5).
Naive Solution A straightforward approach would be to calculate the average for every possible subarray of length k. For each starting point, sum the next k numbers and determine the average.</description></item><item><title>725. Split Linked List in Parts</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/725/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/725/</guid><description>LeetCode problem 725
Problem Statement The problem asks you to divide a given singly linked list into k different parts such that the sizes of these parts are as nearly equal as possible. The parts should appear in the same order as in the original list, and earlier parts should not be smaller than later parts.
Naive Solution A naive approach would involve counting the length of the list and then traversing the list multiple times to create each part.</description></item><item><title>1004. Max Consecutive Ones III</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1004/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1004/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem 1004
Problem Statement Given a binary array nums and an integer k, the task is to return the maximum number of consecutive 1&amp;rsquo;s in the array, with the possibility to flip at most k 0&amp;rsquo;s.
Naive Solution A straight forward approach is to try flipping every combination of k zeros and checking for the longest sequence of 1&amp;rsquo;s. This would involve nested loops, with the outer loop iterating through the array and the inner loops flipping zeros and calculating sequences of 1&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>1071. Greatest Common Divisor of Strings</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1071/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1071/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement The problem is about finding a greatest common divisor (GCD) of two strings. The term &amp;ldquo;GCD&amp;rdquo; might be familiar from mathematics, as the largest number that divides two numbers without leaving a remainder. Here, we extend the idea to strings: a string x is a GCD of strings str1 and str2 if x can be repeatedly appended to itself to obtain str1 and str2.
Naive Solution A naive approach would be to find all possible divisors of str1 and str2, and then find the largest common divisor.</description></item><item><title>1431. Kids With the Greatest Number of Candies</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1431/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1431/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement The problem requires us to find out which kids can potentially have the greatest number of candies if they are given all the extra candies. The information about the number of candies each kid has and the number of extra candies available is given.
Naive Solution A naive approach to this problem would be to iterate over the candies array for each kid and check if adding the extra candies to the kid&amp;rsquo;s current candies makes it equal to or greater than the maximum candies any kid has.</description></item><item><title>1456. Maximum Number of Vowels in a Substring of Given Length</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1456/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1456/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem 1456
Problem Statement Given a string s and an integer k, the task is to return the maximum number of vowel letters in any substring of s with length k.
Vowel letters in English are &amp;lsquo;a&amp;rsquo;, &amp;rsquo;e&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;i&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;o&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;u&amp;rsquo;.
Naive Solution The most straightforward solution to this problem is to take every possible substring of length k and count the number of vowels in each of them. This can be done using nested loops. The outer loop runs through each character in the string while the inner loop counts the vowels for each substring of length k.</description></item><item><title>1493. Longest Subarray of 1's After Deleting One Element</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1493/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1493/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem 1493
Problem Statement Given a binary array nums, you should delete one element from it. The goal is to return the size of the longest subarray containing only 1&amp;rsquo;s after this deletion. If no such subarray exists, return 0.
Naive Solution A straightforward approach is to manually try deleting each element in the array and checking the length of the longest sequence of 1&amp;rsquo;s. This would involve nested loops: an outer loop for deleting an element and an inner loop to check sequences of 1&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>1768. Merge Strings Alternately</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1768/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1768/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement The task is to merge two strings alternately, i.e., take one character from the first string, then one from the second, then again from the first, and so on. If one string finishes before the other, the remaining characters from the longer string are appended at the end.
Naive Solution A naive approach could involve maintaining two pointers, one for each string, and incrementally appending characters from each string to the result. Once we reach the end of one string, we append the rest of the other string to the result.</description></item><item><title>2352. Equal Row and Column Pairs</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/2352/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/2352/</guid><description>LeetCode problem 2352
Problem Statement You are given a square grid of integers, specifically a 0-indexed n×n matrix named grid. The objective is to determine how many pairs of rows and columns in the grid are identical in terms of their content and order.
To elucidate, if row $r_i$ and column $c_j$ have the same integers in the exact same sequence, they are considered an &amp;ldquo;equal&amp;rdquo; pair. The challenge is to count all such pairs in the given matrix.</description></item><item><title>2839. Check if Strings Can be Made Equal With Operations I</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/2839/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/2839/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem
Problem Statement You are given two strings s1 and s2, both of length 4, consisting of lowercase English letters. The objective is to find out if it&amp;rsquo;s possible to make the two strings equal by swapping certain pairs of characters.
Naive Solution A naive approach would be to try out all possible swap combinations. However, this can be very inefficient, especially when the strings have a large number of characters.
Hints &amp;amp; Tips Observe that the swapping condition is quite specific: j - i = 2.</description></item><item><title>2840. Check if Strings Can be Made Equal With Operations II</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/2840/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/2840/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem 2840
Problem Statement You are given two strings s1 and s2, both of length n, consisting of lowercase English letters. You can apply certain operations to make them equal. The question is, is it possible?
Naive Solution A naive approach would be to try all possible swap operations and compare the two strings at each step, which would be highly inefficient.
Hints &amp;amp; Tips Observe that swapping can only occur at indices i and j where j - i is even.</description></item><item><title>2841. Maximum Sum of Almost Unique Subarray</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/2841/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/2841/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem 2841
Problem Statement You are given an integer array nums and two positive integers m and k.
The task is to return the maximum sum out of all almost unique subarrays of length k of nums. If no such subarray exists, return 0.
A subarray is almost unique if it contains at least m pairwise distinct elements.
Naive Solution A naive solution would be to generate all the possible subarrays of length k and check each one to see if it is almost unique and what its sum is.</description></item><item><title>2842. Count K-Subsequences of a String with Maximum Beauty</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/2842/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/2842/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement You are given a string s and an integer k. A k-subsequence is a subsequence of s, having length k, and all its characters are unique. The beauty of a k-subsequence is the sum of f(c) for every character c in the k-subsequence. Here, f(c) denotes the number of times the character c occurs in s.
The task is to find the number of k-subsequences whose beauty is maximum among all k-subsequences. Return the answer modulo $(10^9 + 7)$.</description></item><item><title>2844. Minimum Operations to Make a Special Number</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/2844/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/2844/</guid><description>LeetCode problem 2844
Problem Statement You are given a 0-indexed string num representing a non-negative integer. In one operation, you can pick any digit of num and delete it. Note that if you delete all the digits of num, num becomes 0.
Return the minimum number of operations required to make num special. An integer x is considered special if it is divisible by 25.
Naive Solution A naive approach to solving this problem might involve recursively generating all possible substrings of the input string, checking each one for divisibility by 25.</description></item></channel></rss>