<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloudformation on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/cloudformation/</link><description>Recent content in Cloudformation on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/cloudformation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CloudFormation</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/cloudformation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/cloudformation/</guid><description>About CloudF­orm­ation enables the user to design &amp;amp; provision AWS infras­tru­cture deploy­ments predic­tably &amp;amp; repeat­edly
Documentation User Guide Terminology Component Description Templates The JSON or YAML text file that contains the instructions for building out the AWS environment Stacks The entire environment described by the template and created, updated, and deleted as a single unit StackSets AWS CloudFormation StackSets extends the functionality of stacks by enabling you to create, update, or delete stacks across multiple accounts and regions with a single operation Change Sets A summary of proposed changes to your stack that will allow you to see how those changes might impact your existing resources before implementing them Template The main sections in a CloudFormation template:</description></item><item><title>Setup OpenVPN Server on AWS EC2 Ubuntu</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/stories/002-openvpn-aws-ec2-setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/stories/002-openvpn-aws-ec2-setup/</guid><description>Today, I embarked on a journey to create an accessible, affordable, and easy-to-use VPN solution that anyone can set up on their devices using AWS.
Finding a reasonably priced solution was critical. I opted for Amazon&amp;rsquo;s t3a.nano ARM Ubuntu image, which costs ~$0.0047/hour ~ $3.8/month.
Various Amazon EC2 instances and their prices are listed on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s On-Demand Pricing page.
Here is the list of all Ubuntu AMI images to identify the appropriate image for the project. The selected image combined with the CloudFormation template, which was inspired by the AWS CloudFormation General Reference, provides a seamless and consistent user experience.</description></item></channel></rss>