<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Network on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/network/</link><description>Recent content in Network on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>nmap - cheatsheet</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/nmap-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/nmap-cheatsheet/</guid><description>Scanning Options Nmap Option Description 10.10.10.0/24 Target network range. -sn Disables port scanning. -Pn Disables ICMP Echo Requests -n Disables DNS Resolution. -PE Performs the ping scan by using ICMP Echo Requests against the target. --packet-trace Shows all packets sent and received. --reason Displays the reason for a specific result. --disable-arp-ping Disables ARP Ping Requests. --top-ports=&amp;lt;num&amp;gt; Scans the specified top ports that have been defined as most frequent. -p- Scan all ports. -p22-110 Scan all ports between 22 and 110.</description></item><item><title>Wireless access point with hostapd on Debian</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/wireless-access-point/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/wireless-access-point/</guid><description>Configure network traffic routing and Network Address Translation (NAT) using iptables.
Configure the system to forward packets from one network interface to another, applying NAT to the packets going out of the eth0 interface.
Network configuration where the system is intended to function as a router or gateway between two networks (e.g., forwarding packets from a Wi-Fi network to an Ethernet network).
kali@kali:~$ sudo iptables -t nat -F kali@kali:~$ kali@kali:~$ sudo iptables -F kali@kali:~$ kali@kali:~$ sudo iptables -t nat -A POSTROUTING -o eth0 -j MASQUERADE kali@kali:~$ kali@kali:~$ sudo iptables -A FORWARD -i wlan0 -o eth0 -j ACCEPT kali@kali:~$ kali@kali:~$ echo 1 | sudo tee /proc/sys/net/ipv4/ip_forward # (DNS, dhcp still required) kali@kali:~$ 1.</description></item><item><title>How to disable IPv6 on Debian/Kali Linux</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/howto-disable-ipv6-on-debian/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/linux/howto-disable-ipv6-on-debian/</guid><description>TL;DR git clone https://github.com/romankurnovskii/kali-shortcuts.git cd kali-shortcuts chmod +x disable_ipv6.sh sudo ./disable_ipv6.sh Edit sysctl Configuration In the terminal, type sudo vi /etc/sysctl.conf and press Enter. This opens the sysctl.conf file in the text editor with root privileges. Add IPv6 Disable Lines At the end of the file, add the following lines: net.ipv6.conf.all.disable_ipv6 = 1 net.ipv6.conf.default.disable_ipv6 = 1 net.ipv6.conf.lo.disable_ipv6 = 1 These lines will disable IPv6 on all network interfaces, including the loopback interface.
Save and Exit Save /etc/sysctl.conf and exit text editor Apply Changes To apply the changes without rebooting, run `sudo sysctl -p`` in the terminal.</description></item></channel></rss>