<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LeetCodeTop75 on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/categories/leetcodetop75/</link><description>Recent content in LeetCodeTop75 on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/categories/leetcodetop75/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>11. Container With Most Water</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/11/</guid><description>LeetCode problem 11
Problem Statement The problem involves an array of integers height, where each element represents the height of a line. These lines, along with the x-axis, form a series of containers. Your goal is to find the two lines that form the container with the greatest area.
Naive Solution The naive solution is to consider all pairs of lines and calculate the area of water each pair can contain. You would keep track of the maximum area encountered.</description></item><item><title>13. Roman to Integer</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/13/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Roman numerals are represented by seven different symbols: I, V, X, L, C, D and M.
Symbol Value I 1 V 5 X 10 L 50 C 100 D 500 M 1000 For example, 2 is written as II in Roman numeral, just two ones added together. 12 is written as XII, which is simply X + II. The number 27 is written as XXVII, which is XX + V + II.
Roman numerals are usually written largest to smallest from left to right.</description></item><item><title>LeetCode Top 75</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode75/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode75/</guid><description>Array / String # Problem Difficulty 1 1768. Merge Strings Alternately Easy 2 1071. Greatest Common Divisor of Strings Easy 3 1431. Kids With the Greatest Number of Candies Easy 4 605. Can Place Flowers Easy 5 345. Reverse Vowels of a String Easy 6 151. Reverse Words in a String Medium 7 238. Product of Array Except Self Medium 8 334. Increasing Triplet Subsequence Medium 9 443. String Compression Medium Two Pointers # Problem Difficulty 10 283.</description></item><item><title>151. Reverse Words in a String</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/151/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/151/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement The problem is about reversing the order of words in a given string s. Each word in s is defined as a sequence of non-space characters and the words are separated by at least one space. You are expected to return a string with the words in reversed order and separated by a single space. It is important to note that s may contain leading or trailing spaces or multiple spaces between two words, but the returned string should not contain any extra spaces.</description></item><item><title>238. Product of Array Except Self</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/238/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/238/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement The problem is to find a product of all elements in the given integer array nums, except for the i-th element, and return a new array with the results. You must design an algorithm that runs in O(n) time and doesn&amp;rsquo;t use the division operation. The challenge here is to solve this problem with O(1) extra space complexity.
Naive Solution A naive solution could be to calculate the product of all elements in the array, then iterate through the array and replace each element with the total product divided by the element.</description></item><item><title>283. Move Zeroes</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/283/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/283/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement The problem is asking to move all zeros in an integer array to the end of the array while maintaining the relative order of the non-zero elements. You must do this in-place without making a copy of the array.
Naive Solution A naive solution could be to create a new list, iterate over the array, add non-zero elements to the new list and count zero elements. Then extend the new list with the same amount of zeros as counted.</description></item><item><title>334. Increasing Triplet Subsequence</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/334/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/334/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement The task is to determine if the given list of numbers contains an increasing subsequence of length three. This means we need to find three indices i, j, and k in the list such that i &amp;lt; j &amp;lt; k and nums[i] &amp;lt; nums[j] &amp;lt; nums[k].
Naive Solution One possible naive solution is to use three nested loops to go through all possible triples in the list and check if they are increasing. But this solution is very inefficient, has a time complexity of O(n³), and does not meet the follow-up constraints of the problem.</description></item><item><title>345. Reverse Vowels of a String</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/345/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/345/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given a string s, the task is to reverse only all the vowels in the string and return it. The vowels are &amp;lsquo;a&amp;rsquo;, &amp;rsquo;e&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;i&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;o&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;u&amp;rsquo;, and they can appear in both lower and upper cases, more than once.
Naive Solution The naive approach to solve this problem would be to:
Initialize an empty string result. Traverse the given string s from the start to the end. If the current character is a vowel, find the next vowel in the string starting from the end, add it to result, and remove it from the string.</description></item><item><title>392. Is Subsequence</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/392/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/392/</guid><description>LeetCode problem 392
Problem Statement Given two strings s and t, you need to determine if s is a subsequence of t. To be a subsequence, you can remove characters from t without reordering to form s.
Naive Solution The naive approach would be to generate all subsequences of string t and then check if string s is one of them. However, generating all subsequences of t can be computationally expensive especially when the length of t is large.</description></item><item><title>443. String Compression</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/443/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/443/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given a list of characters, chars, you are required to compress the list using the following algorithm:
Start with an empty string, s. For each group of consecutive repeating characters in chars: If the group&amp;rsquo;s length is 1, append the character to s. Otherwise, append the character followed by the group&amp;rsquo;s length. The compressed string s should be stored back in the chars list. The length of the group that is 10 or longer will be split into multiple characters in chars.</description></item><item><title>605. Can Place Flowers</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/605/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/605/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement In the &amp;ldquo;Can Place Flowers&amp;rdquo; problem, we have a long flowerbed in which some of the plots are planted with flowers (represented by 1&amp;rsquo;s in an integer array), and some are not (represented by 0&amp;rsquo;s). We must determine whether we can plant a certain number of new flowers (denoted as &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;) in the flowerbed without violating the no-adjacent-flowers rule, i.e., flowers cannot be planted in adjacent plots.
Naive Solution A simple approach to this problem would be to go through each plot in the flowerbed and try to plant a flower if the plot is empty and its neighboring plots are also empty.</description></item><item><title>643. Maximum Average Subarray I</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/643/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/643/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given an integer array nums consisting of n elements and an integer k, find a contiguous subarray whose length is equal to k that has the maximum average value and return this value. The result must be accurate up to a decimal point of 10^(-5).
Naive Solution A straightforward approach would be to calculate the average for every possible subarray of length k. For each starting point, sum the next k numbers and determine the average.</description></item><item><title>1004. Max Consecutive Ones III</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1004/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1004/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem 1004
Problem Statement Given a binary array nums and an integer k, the task is to return the maximum number of consecutive 1&amp;rsquo;s in the array, with the possibility to flip at most k 0&amp;rsquo;s.
Naive Solution A straight forward approach is to try flipping every combination of k zeros and checking for the longest sequence of 1&amp;rsquo;s. This would involve nested loops, with the outer loop iterating through the array and the inner loops flipping zeros and calculating sequences of 1&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>1071. Greatest Common Divisor of Strings</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1071/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1071/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement The problem is about finding a greatest common divisor (GCD) of two strings. The term &amp;ldquo;GCD&amp;rdquo; might be familiar from mathematics, as the largest number that divides two numbers without leaving a remainder. Here, we extend the idea to strings: a string x is a GCD of strings str1 and str2 if x can be repeatedly appended to itself to obtain str1 and str2.
Naive Solution A naive approach would be to find all possible divisors of str1 and str2, and then find the largest common divisor.</description></item><item><title>1431. Kids With the Greatest Number of Candies</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1431/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1431/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement The problem requires us to find out which kids can potentially have the greatest number of candies if they are given all the extra candies. The information about the number of candies each kid has and the number of extra candies available is given.
Naive Solution A naive approach to this problem would be to iterate over the candies array for each kid and check if adding the extra candies to the kid&amp;rsquo;s current candies makes it equal to or greater than the maximum candies any kid has.</description></item><item><title>1456. Maximum Number of Vowels in a Substring of Given Length</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1456/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1456/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem 1456
Problem Statement Given a string s and an integer k, the task is to return the maximum number of vowel letters in any substring of s with length k.
Vowel letters in English are &amp;lsquo;a&amp;rsquo;, &amp;rsquo;e&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;i&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;o&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;u&amp;rsquo;.
Naive Solution The most straightforward solution to this problem is to take every possible substring of length k and count the number of vowels in each of them. This can be done using nested loops. The outer loop runs through each character in the string while the inner loop counts the vowels for each substring of length k.</description></item><item><title>1493. Longest Subarray of 1's After Deleting One Element</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1493/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/1493/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem 1493
Problem Statement Given a binary array nums, you should delete one element from it. The goal is to return the size of the longest subarray containing only 1&amp;rsquo;s after this deletion. If no such subarray exists, return 0.
Naive Solution A straightforward approach is to manually try deleting each element in the array and checking the length of the longest sequence of 1&amp;rsquo;s. This would involve nested loops: an outer loop for deleting an element and an inner loop to check sequences of 1&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>1768. Merge Strings Alternately</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1768/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1768/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement The task is to merge two strings alternately, i.e., take one character from the first string, then one from the second, then again from the first, and so on. If one string finishes before the other, the remaining characters from the longer string are appended at the end.
Naive Solution A naive approach could involve maintaining two pointers, one for each string, and incrementally appending characters from each string to the result. Once we reach the end of one string, we append the rest of the other string to the result.</description></item></channel></rss>