<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Trading on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/categories/trading/</link><description>Recent content in Trading on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/categories/trading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Average True Range (ATR) - Volatility Indicator</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/atr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/atr/</guid><description>About The Average True Range (ATR) is a technical analysis indicator that measures market volatility by decomposing the entire range of an asset price for that period. It was developed by J. Welles Wilder Jr. and introduced in his book &amp;ldquo;New Concepts in Technical Trading Systems&amp;rdquo; in 1978.
Calculating Formula ATR is calculated based on the true range (TR), which is the maximum of the following:
Current High less the current Low Absolute value of (Current High less the previous Close) Absolute value of (Current Low less the previous Close) The ATR is then the moving average over a given period of the TR.</description></item><item><title>EMA - Exponential Moving Average</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/ema/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/ema/</guid><description>About Unlike the SMA, the EMA gives more weight to recent data, making it quicker to respond to price changes.
Calculating Formula EMA = (Close - Previous EMA) * Multiplier + Previous EMA
Where:
Close: the closing price for a given period (Price today/now). Here close prices is for example N: the period of the EMA. Multiplier: 2 / (N + 1) Previous EMA is the EMA of the previous period. The EMA for the first period is just the Close price.</description></item><item><title>Stochastic Oscillator - Momentum Indicator</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/stochastic_oscillator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/stochastic_oscillator/</guid><description>About The Stochastic Oscillator is a momentum indicator that shows the location of the close relative to the high-low range over a set number of periods. It was developed by George Lane in the 1950s.
Calculating Formula The Stochastic Oscillator is calculated using the following formula:
%K = 100[(C - L14) / (H14 - L14)] where:
C = the most recent closing price L14 = the lowest price traded of the 14 previous trading sessions H14 = the highest price traded during the same 14-day period %K = the current value of the stochastic indicator The &amp;ldquo;%D&amp;rdquo; line is then a 3-day simple moving average of %K.</description></item><item><title>Bollinger Bands - Volatility and Price Level Indicator</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/bollinger_bands/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/bollinger_bands/</guid><description>About Bollinger Bands is a technical indicator developed by John Bollinger in the 1980s. It provides a relative definition of high and low prices of a market instrument by creating a band of two standard deviations from a simple moving average (SMA).
Calculating Formula Bollinger Bands consist of three lines:
Middle Line: 20-day simple moving average (SMA) Upper Band: 20-day SMA + (2 * 20-day standard deviation of price) Lower Band: 20-day SMA - (2 * 20-day standard deviation of price) The standard deviation measures how spread out the prices or returns of an asset are on average.</description></item><item><title>MACD - Moving Average Convergence Divergence</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/macd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/macd/</guid><description>About The Moving Average Convergence Divergence (MACD) is a versatile trading indicator used in various forms of trading, including high-frequency trading (HFT).
MACD is a trend-following momentum indicator that shows the relationship between two moving averages of a security’s price.
Calculating Formula The MACD is calculated by subtracting the 26-period Exponential Moving Average (EMA) from the 12-period EMA. A 9-day EMA of the MACD, called the &amp;ldquo;signal line&amp;rdquo;, is then plotted on top of the MACD, functioning as a trigger for buy and sell signals.</description></item><item><title>RSI - Relative Strength Index</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/rsi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/rsi/</guid><description>About The Relative Strength Index (RSI) is a momentum oscillator that measures the speed and change of price movements. Developed by J. Welles Wilder, the RSI is a very popular indicator that is used primarily to identify overbought and oversold conditions in a market.
Calculating The RSI is calculated using the following steps:
Calculate the average gain and the average loss over the specified period (usually 14 periods). Compute the relative strength (RS) which is the ratio of average gain to average loss.</description></item><item><title>SMA - Simple Moving Average</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/sma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/sma/</guid><description>About The Simple Moving Average (SMA) is a technical indicator that calculates the average price over a specific number of periods, and it moves along as new data is added, making it a &amp;ldquo;moving average&amp;rdquo;.
Calculating Formula SMA = (Sum of price data for the last N periods) / N
For example, a 5-period SMA would sum up the last 5 closing prices and divide it by 5 to find the average. It is called a &amp;lsquo;moving&amp;rsquo; average because as new prices become available, the oldest prices are dropped and the average recalculates.</description></item><item><title>Trading indicators</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/posts/trading-indicators/</guid><description>Raw market data Minute Open High Low Close 1 $10.0 $11.0 $9.5 $10.0 2 $10.1 $12.1 $10.0 $12.0 3 $12.2 $15.2 $12.0 $15.0 4 $15.1 $15.1 $13.9 $14.0 5 $14.1 $16.1 $14.0 $16.0 6 $16.1 $16.1 $14.9 $15.0 7 $15.1 $17.1 $15.0 $17.0 8 $17.1 $17.1 $15.9 $16.0 9 $16.1 $18.1 $16.0 $18.0 10 $18.1 $18.1 $16.9 $17.0 11 $17.1 $19.1 $17.0 $19.0 12 $19.1 $19.1 $17.9 $18.0 13 $18.1 $20.1 $18.0 $20.0 14 $20.1 $21.1 $20.0 $21.0 15 $21.</description></item></channel></rss>