<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>s3 on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/categories/s3/</link><description>Recent content in s3 on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href="https://romankurnovskii.com">Roman Kurnovskii&lt;/a> personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/categories/s3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create S3 Bucket</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/create-s3-bucket/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/create-s3-bucket/</guid><description>Creating an Amazon S3 Bucket Introduction You can create an Amazon S3 bucket using the AWS Management Console. As with many other AWS services, you can use the AWS API or CLI (command-line interface) as well.
In this lab step, you will create a new Amazon S3 bucket.
Instructions In the AWS Management Console search bar, enter S3, and click the S3 result under Services: You will be placed in the S3 console.
From the S3 console, click the orange Create Bucket button: Enter a unique Bucket name on the Name and region screen of the wizard: Region: US West (Oregon) (This should be set for you.</description></item><item><title>Create a folder inside S3 Bucket</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/create-folder-s3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/create-folder-s3/</guid><description>Creating a Folder inside an Amazon S3 Bucket Introduction The AWS S3 console allows you to create folders for grouping objects. This can be a very helpful organizational tool. However, in Amazon S3, buckets and objects are the primary resources. A folder simply becomes a prefix for object key names that are virtually archived into it.
Instructions Return to the Buckets menu by clicking here, and click on the calabs-bucket you created earlier. (Reminder: Your bucket name will differ slightly.</description></item><item><title>Upload a file to S3</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/upload-file-to-s3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/upload-file-to-s3/</guid><description>Uploading a File to Amazon S3 Introduction When you upload a folder from your local system or another machine, Amazon S3 uploads all the files and subfolders from the specified local folder to your bucket. It then assigns a key value that is a combination of the uploaded file name and the folder name. In this lab step, you will upload a file to your bucket. The process is similar to uploading a single file, multiple files, or a folder with files in it.</description></item><item><title>Grant public access to S3 Object</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/grant-access-s3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/grant-access-s3/</guid><description>Granting Public Access to an Amazon S3 Object Introduction All uploaded files are private by default and can only be viewed, edited, or downloaded by you. In order to illustrate this point, complete the instructions below.
Note: The terms &amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;object&amp;rdquo; are often used interchangeably when discussing Amazon S3. Technically, Amazon S3 is an object-store. It is not a block storage device and does not contain a file system as your local computer does. However, files such as images, movies, and sound clips are often uploaded from your file system to Amazon S3.</description></item><item><title>Change metadata of S3 Object</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/how-to-change-metadata-s3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/how-to-change-metadata-s3/</guid><description>Changing the Metadata of an Amazon S3 Object Introduction Each object in Amazon S3 has a set of key/value pairs representing its metadata. There are two types of metadata: &amp;ldquo;System metadata&amp;rdquo; (for example, Content-Type and Content-Length) and custom &amp;ldquo;User metadata&amp;rdquo;. User metadata is stored with the object and returned with it.
As an example, you might have your own taxonomy for various images, such as “logo”, “screenshot”, “diagram”, &amp;ldquo;flowchart&amp;rdquo; and so on. In this lab step, you will change the Content-Type of your image to &amp;ldquo;text/plain&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Delete S3 Bucket</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/delete-from-s3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/delete-from-s3/</guid><description>Deleting an Amazon S3 Bucket Introduction You can delete an Amazon S3 bucket using the S3 console. You will delete all objects within the bucket as well.
Instructions In the AWS Management Console search bar, enter S3, and click the S3 result under Services: From the top level of the S3 console, notice the Delete button is not actionable.
2. Check the name of your bucket to select it:
With the bucket selected, click Empty: The Empty bucket form page will load.</description></item><item><title>S3</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/docs/aws-certified-developer-associate/s3/</guid><description>About Amazon S3 (Simple Storage Service) provides object storage through a web service interface.
Amazon S3 Amazon S3 User Guide Price Pay only for what you use. There is no minimum charge.
Price
S3 | EFS | EBS Amazon S3 is an object storage designed for storing large numbers of user files and backups. Good for storing backups and other static data Can be publicly accessible Web interface Object Storage Scalable Slower than EBS and EFS Amazon EBS (Amazon Elastic Block Store) is block storage for Amazon EC2 compute instances - it is similar to hard drives attached to your computers or laptops, but in a virtualized environment.</description></item></channel></rss>