<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LeetCodeTop75 on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/categories/leetcodetop75/</link><description>Recent content in LeetCodeTop75 on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>ru</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/categories/leetcodetop75/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>345. Reverse Vowels of a String</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/345/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/345/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Задача состоит в том, чтобы перевернуть только все гласные в строке и вернуть её. Гласные - это &amp;lsquo;a&amp;rsquo;, &amp;rsquo;e&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;i&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;o&amp;rsquo; и &amp;lsquo;u&amp;rsquo;, и они могут встречаться как в нижнем, так и в верхнем регистре, более одного раза.
Naive Solution Наивное решение этой задачи может быть выполнено следующим образом:
Идентифицируйте все гласные в строке и сохраните их в список. Создайте новую пустую строку. Пройдитесь по исходной строке, и если текущий символ гласный, добавьте в новую строку следующую гласную из списка в обратном порядке.</description></item><item><title>724. Find Pivot Index</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/724/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/724/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given an array of integers nums, the task is to calculate the pivot index of this array. The pivot index is defined as the index where the sum of all the numbers strictly to the left of the index is equal to the sum of all the numbers strictly to the index&amp;rsquo;s right. If no such index exists, return -1.
Naive Solution A naive approach would be to iterate over each index and for each index, calculate the sum of elements to the left and right of the index.</description></item></channel></rss>