<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LeetCode Contest 112 on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/leetcode-contest-112/</link><description>Recent content in LeetCode Contest 112 on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/leetcode-contest-112/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2839. Check if Strings Can be Made Equal With Operations I</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/2839/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/2839/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem
Problem Statement You are given two strings s1 and s2, both of length 4, consisting of lowercase English letters. The objective is to find out if it&amp;rsquo;s possible to make the two strings equal by swapping certain pairs of characters.
Naive Solution A naive approach would be to try out all possible swap combinations. However, this can be very inefficient, especially when the strings have a large number of characters.
Hints &amp;amp; Tips Observe that the swapping condition is quite specific: j - i = 2.</description></item><item><title>2841. Maximum Sum of Almost Unique Subarray</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/2841/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/2841/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem 2841
Problem Statement You are given an integer array nums and two positive integers m and k.
The task is to return the maximum sum out of all almost unique subarrays of length k of nums. If no such subarray exists, return 0.
A subarray is almost unique if it contains at least m pairwise distinct elements.
Naive Solution A naive solution would be to generate all the possible subarrays of length k and check each one to see if it is almost unique and what its sum is.</description></item></channel></rss>