<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Easy on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/easy/</link><description>Recent content in Easy on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/easy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>202. Happy Number</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/202/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/202/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement In this problem, we are given a number n. We have to determine whether this number is a &amp;ldquo;happy&amp;rdquo; number or not. A happy number is a number defined by the following process:
Starting with any positive integer, replace the number by the sum of the squares of its digits. Repeat the process until the number equals 1 (where it will stay), or it loops endlessly in a cycle which does not include 1. Those numbers for which this process ends in 1 are happy.</description></item><item><title>1071. Greatest Common Divisor of Strings</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1071/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1071/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement The problem is about finding a greatest common divisor (GCD) of two strings. The term &amp;ldquo;GCD&amp;rdquo; might be familiar from mathematics, as the largest number that divides two numbers without leaving a remainder. Here, we extend the idea to strings: a string x is a GCD of strings str1 and str2 if x can be repeatedly appended to itself to obtain str1 and str2.
Naive Solution A naive approach would be to find all possible divisors of str1 and str2, and then find the largest common divisor.</description></item><item><title>1768. Merge Strings Alternately</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1768/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1768/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement The task is to merge two strings alternately, i.e., take one character from the first string, then one from the second, then again from the first, and so on. If one string finishes before the other, the remaining characters from the longer string are appended at the end.
Naive Solution A naive approach could involve maintaining two pointers, one for each string, and incrementally appending characters from each string to the result. Once we reach the end of one string, we append the rest of the other string to the result.</description></item></channel></rss>