<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Math on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tags/math/</link><description>Recent content in Math on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>ru</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tags/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2. Add Two Numbers</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/2/</guid><description>You are given two non-empty linked lists representing two non-negative integers. The digits are stored in reverse order, and each of their nodes contains a single digit. Add the two numbers and return the sum as a linked list.
You may assume the two numbers do not contain any leading zero, except the number 0 itself.
Example 1:
Input: l1 = [2,4,3], l2 = [5,6,4] Output: [7,0,8] Explanation: 342 + 465 = 807. First accepted Idea:
Loop through lists add each value to the list reverse list calculate sum create linked list from reversed sum class Solution: def addTwoNumbers(self, l1: Optional[ListNode], l2: Optional[ListNode]) -&amp;gt; Optional[ListNode]: def createLinkedNode(values): head = ListNode(values[0]) current = head for i in values[1:]: node = ListNode(i) current.</description></item><item><title>7. Reverse Integer</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/7/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Given a signed 32-bit integer x, return x with its digits reversed. If reversing x causes the value to go outside the signed 32-bit integer range [-231, 231 - 1], then return 0.
Assume the environment does not allow you to store 64-bit integers (signed or unsigned).
Example 1:
Input: x = 123 Output: 321
Example 2:
Input: x = -123 Output: -321
Example 3:
Input: x = 120 Output: 21
First accepted Idea:
Convert number to int Remove minus if exist (or convert module of number) reverse class Solution: def reverse(self, x: int) -&amp;gt; int: reversed_int = [] str_int = str(x) if x &amp;lt; 0: str_int = str_int[1:] for i in reversed(range(len(str_int))): reversed_int.</description></item><item><title>9. Palindrome Number</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/9/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/9/</guid><description>LeetCode задача
Задача Определите, является ли целое число палиндромом, не преобразуя его в строку.
Подсказки Переворачивая число и сравнивая его с оригиналом, мы можем определить, является ли оно палиндромом.
Подход Вместо того чтобы преобразовывать число в строку, мы можем перевернуть его цифры с использованием математических операций, а затем сравнить перевернутое число с оригинальным.
Алгоритм Если число отрицательное, то это не палиндром. Инициализируем переменную для перевернутого числа: мы будем создавать это число шаг за шагом. Переворачиваем число: Это достигается путем последовательного взятия последней цифры числа и добавления её к текущему общему количеству после сдвига текущих цифр этого общего числа.</description></item><item><title>13. Roman to Integer</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/13/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Roman numerals are represented by seven different symbols: I, V, X, L, C, D and M.
Symbol Value I 1 V 5 X 10 L 50 C 100 D 500 M 1000 For example, 2 is written as II in Roman numeral, just two ones added together. 12 is written as XII, which is simply X + II. The number 27 is written as XXVII, which is XX + V + II.
Roman numerals are usually written largest to smallest from left to right.</description></item><item><title>29. Divide Two Integers</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/29/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/29/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Given two integers dividend and divisor, divide two integers without using multiplication, division, and mod operator.
The integer division should truncate toward zero, which means losing its fractional part. For example, 8.345 would be truncated to 8, and -2.7335 would be truncated to -2.
Return the quotient after dividing dividend by divisor.
Note: Assume we are dealing with an environment that could only store integers within the 32-bit signed integer range: [−231, 231 − 1]. For this problem, if the quotient is strictly greater than 231 - 1, then return 231 - 1, and if the quotient is strictly less than -231, then return -231.</description></item><item><title>33. Search in Rotated Sorted Array</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/33/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/33/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
There is an integer array nums sorted in ascending order (with distinct values).
Prior to being passed to your function, nums is possibly rotated at an unknown pivot index k (1 &amp;lt;= k &amp;lt; nums.length) such that the resulting array is [nums[k], nums[k+1], ..., nums[n-1], nums[0], nums[1], ..., nums[k-1]] (0-indexed). For example, [0,1,2,4,5,6,7] might be rotated at pivot index 3 and become [4,5,6,7,0,1,2].
Given the array nums after the possible rotation and an integer target, return the index of target if it is in nums, or -1 if it is not in nums.</description></item><item><title>48. Rotate Image</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/48/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/48/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
You are given an n x n 2D matrix representing an image, rotate the image by 90 degrees (clockwise).
You have to rotate the image in-place, which means you have to modify the input 2D matrix directly. DO NOT allocate another 2D matrix and do the rotation.
Example 1:
Input: matrix = [[1,2,3],[4,5,6],[7,8,9]] Output: [[7,4,1],[8,5,2],[9,6,3]] Example 2:
Input: matrix = [[5,1,9,11],[2,4,8,10],[13,3,6,7],[15,14,12,16]] Output: [[15,13,2,5],[14,3,4,1],[12,6,8,9],[16,7,10,11]] Idea:
class Solution: def rotate(self, matrix: List[List[int]]) -&amp;gt; None: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; Do not return anything, modify matrix in-place instead.</description></item><item><title>50. Pow(x, n)</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/50/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/50/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Implement pow(x, n), which calculates x raised to the power n (i.e., x^n).
Example 1:
Input: x = 2.00000, n = 10 Output: 1024.00000 Example 2:
Input: x = 2.10000, n = 3 Output: 9.26100 Example 3:
Input: x = 2.00000, n = -2 Output: 0.25000 Explanation: 2-2 = 1/22 = 1/4 = 0.25 Approach 1:
class Solution: def myPow(self, x: float, n: int) -&amp;gt; float: return x ** n Approach 2:
Recursive
class Solution: def myPow(self, x, n): if not n: return 1 if n &amp;lt; 0: return 1 / self.</description></item><item><title>62. Unique Paths</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/62/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/62/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
There is a robot on an m x n grid. The robot is initially located at the top-left corner (i.e., grid[0][0]). The robot tries to move to the bottom-right corner (i.e., grid[m - 1][n - 1]). The robot can only move either down or right at any point in time.
Given the two integers m and n, return the number of possible unique paths that the robot can take to reach the bottom-right corner.
The test cases are generated so that the answer will be less than or equal to 2 * 10^9.</description></item><item><title>66. Plus One</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/66/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/66/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
You are given a large integer represented as an integer array digits, where each digits[i] is the ith digit of the integer. The digits are ordered from most significant to least significant in left-to-right order. The large integer does not contain any leading 0&amp;rsquo;s.
Increment the large integer by one and return the resulting array of digits.
Example 1:
Input: digits = [1,2,3] Output: [1,2,4] Explanation: The array represents the integer 123. Incrementing by one gives 123 + 1 = 124.</description></item><item><title>69. Sqrt(x)</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/69/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/69/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Given a non-negative integer x, return the square root of x rounded down to the nearest integer. The returned integer should be non-negative as well.
You must not use any built-in exponent function or operator.
For example, do not use pow(x, 0.5) in c++ or x ** 0.5 in python.
Example 1:
Input: x = 4 Output: 2 Explanation: The square root of 4 is 2, so we return 2. Example 2:
Input: x = 8 Output: 2 Explanation: The square root of 8 is 2.</description></item><item><title>70. Climbing Stairs</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/70/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/70/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
You are climbing a staircase. It takes n steps to reach the top.
Each time you can either climb 1 or 2 steps. In how many distinct ways can you climb to the top?
Example 1:
Input: n = 2 Output: 2 Explanation: There are two ways to climb to the top. 1. 1 step + 1 step 2. 2 steps Example 2:
Input: n = 3 Output: 3 Explanation: There are three ways to climb to the top.</description></item><item><title>118. Pascal's Triangle</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/118/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/118/</guid><description>LeetCode задача 118
Задача Дано целое число numRows. Верните первые numRows строк Треугольника Паскаля.
В Треугольнике Паскаля каждое число является суммой двух чисел, находящихся непосредственно над ним.
Подсказки Для построения каждой следующей строки можно использовать последнюю строку в текущей итерации. Например, если есть строка [1, 2, 1], то следующая строка начнется и закончится с 1, а числа внутри будут получены путем сложения пар чисел: 1+2 и 2+1.
Подход Для того чтобы построить Треугольник Паскаля, начнем с первой строки, состоящей только из числа 1.</description></item><item><title>166. Fraction to Recurring Decimal</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/166/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/ru/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/medium/166/</guid><description>LeetCode problem 166
Problem Statement Given two integers representing the numerator and denominator of a fraction, return the fraction in string format. If the fractional part is repeating, enclose the repeating part in parentheses.
This problem is about converting a fraction to its decimal representation in string format. The tricky part is dealing with repeating decimals. If a decimal repeats, we should enclose the repeating part in parentheses.
For example, if we have a fraction 1/3, the decimal representation would be 0.</description></item></channel></rss>