<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Easy on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/</link><description>Recent content in Easy on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. Two Sum</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/1/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Given an array of integers nums and an integer target, return indices of the two numbers such that they add up to target.
You may assume that each input would have exactly one solution, and you may not use the same element twice.
You can return the answer in any order.
Example 1:
Input: nums = [2,7,11,15], target = 9 Output: [0,1] Explanation: Because nums[0] + nums[1] == 9, we return [0, 1]. Topics: array, hash table</description></item><item><title>13. Roman to Integer</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/13/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Roman numerals are represented by seven different symbols: I, V, X, L, C, D and M.
Symbol Value I 1 V 5 X 10 L 50 C 100 D 500 M 1000 For example, 2 is written as II in Roman numeral, just two ones added together. 12 is written as XII, which is simply X + II. The number 27 is written as XXVII, which is XX + V + II.
Roman numerals are usually written largest to smallest from left to right.</description></item><item><title>14. Longest Common Prefix</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/14/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/14/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Write a function to find the longest common prefix string amongst an array of strings.
If there is no common prefix, return an empty string &amp;quot;&amp;quot;.
Example 1:
Input: strs = [&amp;quot;flower&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;flow&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;flight&amp;quot;] Output: &amp;quot;fl&amp;quot; Example 2:
Input: strs = [&amp;quot;dog&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;racecar&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;car&amp;quot;] Output: &amp;quot;&amp;quot; Explanation: There is no common prefix among the input strings. First accepted Idea:
class Solution: def longestCommonPrefix(self, strs: List[str]) -&amp;gt; str: strs.sort() l = strs[0] r = strs[-1] if l == r: return l res = &amp;#34;&amp;#34; for i in range(0, len(l)): if l[i] == r[i]: res += l[i] else: return res return res</description></item><item><title>20. Valid Parentheses</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/20/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Given a string s containing just the characters '(', ')', '{', '}', '[' and ']', determine if the input string is valid.
An input string is valid if:
Open brackets must be closed by the same type of brackets. Open brackets must be closed in the correct order. Every close bracket has a corresponding open bracket of the same type. Example 1:
Input: s = &amp;quot;()[]{}&amp;quot; Output: true Example 2:
Input: s = &amp;quot;()[]{}&amp;quot; Output: true First accepted Idea:</description></item><item><title>21. Merge Two Sorted Lists</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/21/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/21/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
You are given the heads of two sorted linked lists list1 and list2.
Merge the two lists in a one sorted list. The list should be made by splicing together the nodes of the first two lists.
Return the head of the merged linked list.
Example 1:
Input: list1 = [1,2,4], list2 = [1,3,4] Output: [1,1,2,3,4,4] Example 2:
Input: list1 = [], list2 = [0] Output: [0] First accepted Idea:
Get smallest head. Loop and update its next.</description></item><item><title>26. Remove Duplicates from Sorted Array</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/26/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/26/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Given an integer array nums sorted in non-decreasing order, remove the duplicates in-place such that each unique element appears only once. The relative order of the elements should be kept the same.
Since it is impossible to change the length of the array in some languages, you must instead have the result be placed in the first part of the array nums. More formally, if there are k elements after removing the duplicates, then the first k elements of nums should hold the final result.</description></item><item><title>66. Plus One</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/66/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/66/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
You are given a large integer represented as an integer array digits, where each digits[i] is the ith digit of the integer. The digits are ordered from most significant to least significant in left-to-right order. The large integer does not contain any leading 0&amp;rsquo;s.
Increment the large integer by one and return the resulting array of digits.
Example 1:
Input: digits = [1,2,3] Output: [1,2,4] Explanation: The array represents the integer 123. Incrementing by one gives 123 + 1 = 124.</description></item><item><title>69. Sqrt(x)</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/69/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/69/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Given a non-negative integer x, return the square root of x rounded down to the nearest integer. The returned integer should be non-negative as well.
You must not use any built-in exponent function or operator.
For example, do not use pow(x, 0.5) in c++ or x ** 0.5 in python.
Example 1:
Input: x = 4 Output: 2 Explanation: The square root of 4 is 2, so we return 2. Example 2:
Input: x = 8 Output: 2 Explanation: The square root of 8 is 2.</description></item><item><title>70. Climbing Stairs</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/70/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/70/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
You are climbing a staircase. It takes n steps to reach the top.
Each time you can either climb 1 or 2 steps. In how many distinct ways can you climb to the top?
Example 1:
Input: n = 2 Output: 2 Explanation: There are two ways to climb to the top. 1. 1 step + 1 step 2. 2 steps Example 2:
Input: n = 3 Output: 3 Explanation: There are three ways to climb to the top.</description></item><item><title>88. Merge Sorted Array</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/88/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/88/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
You are given two integer arrays nums1 and nums2, sorted in non-decreasing order, and two integers m and n, representing the number of elements in nums1 and nums2 respectively.
Merge nums1 and nums2 into a single array sorted in non-decreasing order.
The final sorted array should not be returned by the function, but instead be stored inside the array nums1. To accommodate this, nums1 has a length of m + n, where the first m elements denote the elements that should be merged, and the last n elements are set to 0 and should be ignored.</description></item><item><title>94. Binary Tree Inorder Traversal</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/94/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/94/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Given the root of a binary tree, return the inorder traversal of its nodes' values.
Example 1:
Input: root = [1,null,2,3] Output: [1,3,2] Example 2:
Input: root = [] Output: [] Example 3:
Input: root = [1] Output: [1] Thoughts Don&amp;rsquo;t understand what needed. Why:
1-null-2-3 becomes 1-3-2 [1,2,5,7,8,9,10] becomes [7,2,8,1,9,5,10] In 1-null-2-3 1 becomes the first because we loop to its left node which is null, then come back and first value here is 1.</description></item><item><title>141. Linked List Cycle</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/141/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/141/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
class Solution: def hasCycle(self, head: Optional[ListNode]) -&amp;gt; bool: visited = set() cur = head while cur: if cur.next in visited: return True cur = cur.next visited.add(cur) return False</description></item><item><title>160. Intersection of Two Linked Lists</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/160/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/160/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Solution 1 Using hashmap.
# Definition for singly-linked list. class ListNode: def __init__(self, x): self.val = x self.next = None class Solution: def getIntersectionNode(self, headA: ListNode, headB: ListNode): nodes = set() cur = headA while cur: nodes.add(cur) cur = cur.next cur = headB while cur: if cur in nodes: return cur cur = cur.next return None Solution 2 Initialize two pointers, one for each head. Move each pointer to the next node in its list. If a pointer reaches the end of its list, move it to the start of the other list.</description></item><item><title>171. Excel Sheet Column Number</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/171/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/171/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
The column titles in an Excel sheet are designed similar to a base-26 number system. The columns start from &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; (which is 1) to &amp;lsquo;Z&amp;rsquo; (which is 26), then after &amp;lsquo;Z&amp;rsquo;, the column titles go to &amp;lsquo;AA&amp;rsquo; (which is 27), &amp;lsquo;AB&amp;rsquo; (28), and so on.
This problem is essentially asking us to convert a base-26 number (represented by uppercase English letters) to a decimal number.
That means that for each &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; index in columnTitle we already pass alphabet.</description></item><item><title>190. Reverse Bits</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/190/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/190/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
This task involves understanding how binary representation works. An unsigned integer is a 32-bit value, where each bit represents a power of 2, from 2^0 (the least significant bit) to 2^31 (the most significant bit).
Unsigned Integers (often called &amp;ldquo;uints&amp;rdquo;) are just like integers (whole numbers) but have the property that they don&amp;rsquo;t have a + or - sign associated with them. Thus they are always non-negative (zero or positive).
Naive Solution A naive solution to this problem could involve converting the number to a binary string, reversing the string, and then converting it back to an integer.</description></item><item><title>191. Number of 1 Bits</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/191/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/191/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given an integer value represented in binary format, we need to count the number of &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; bits in its binary representation.
Naive Solution The naive solution for this problem would be to convert the binary number into a string and then simply iterate over the string and count the number of &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo;s. However, this solution is not optimal and is not taking advantage of the properties of binary numbers.
Algorithm The optimal solution for this problem involves using bitwise operation.</description></item><item><title>202. Happy Number</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/202/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/202/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement In this problem, we are given a number n. We have to determine whether this number is a &amp;ldquo;happy&amp;rdquo; number or not. A happy number is a number defined by the following process:
Starting with any positive integer, replace the number by the sum of the squares of its digits. Repeat the process until the number equals 1 (where it will stay), or it loops endlessly in a cycle which does not include 1. Those numbers for which this process ends in 1 are happy.</description></item><item><title>234. Palindrome Linked List</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/234/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/easy/other/234/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given the head of a singly linked list, return true if it is a palindrome or false otherwise.
Naive Solution A simple solution to this problem is to:
traverse the linked list storing the value of each node in an array. Then, we could compare the array with its reversed version.
If they match, the linked list is a palindrome. Otherwise, it is not.
This solution takes O(n) time (where n is the number of nodes in the list), as we need to traverse the list once.</description></item></channel></rss>