<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hard on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/</link><description>Recent content in Hard on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>332. Reconstruct Itinerary</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/332/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/332/</guid><description>LeetCode problem
Problem Statement Given a list of airline tickets represented by pairs of departure and arrival airports [from, to], reconstruct the itinerary in order. All of the tickets belong to a man who departs from &amp;ldquo;JFK&amp;rdquo;, thus, the itinerary must begin with &amp;ldquo;JFK&amp;rdquo;. If there are multiple valid itineraries, you should return the itinerary that has the smallest lexical order when read as a single string.
Naive Solution One naive solution would be to use backtracking and try all possible combinations of tickets to form a valid itinerary.</description></item><item><title>847. Shortest Path Visiting All Nodes</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/847/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/847/</guid><description>LeetCode problem 847
Problem Statement Given an undirected, connected graph of n nodes labeled from 0 to n - 1. An array graph is provided where graph[i] is a list of all the nodes connected with node i by an edge. The objective is to determine the length of the shortest path that visits every node.
It&amp;rsquo;s permissible to start and stop at any node, revisit nodes multiple times, and reuse edges.
Naive Solution A naive approach would be to attempt all possible paths (brute force) until all nodes are visited.</description></item><item><title>1359. Count All Valid Pickup and Delivery Options</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/1359/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/1359/</guid><description>LeetCode problem 1359
Problem Statement You&amp;rsquo;re tasked with finding all valid sequences of pickup and delivery events for n orders such that for every order, the delivery always comes after its respective pickup. Because the answer can be immense, you&amp;rsquo;re to return the result modulo (10^9 + 7).
Naive Solution A straightforward approach might be to generate all potential permutations of pickup and delivery actions and then exclude the unsuitable ones. However, this method would be exceedingly inefficient and would not scale for larger n values.</description></item><item><title>1420. Build Array Where You Can Find The Maximum Exactly K Comparisons</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/1420/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/1420/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem 1420
Problem Statement In this problem, we have three integers, n, m, and k. We need to construct an array arr having the following properties:
It consists of exactly n integers. Each integer in the array is between 1 and m inclusive. After executing a certain algorithm on arr, we get a value known as search_cost. Our goal is to ensure search_cost is equal to k. The main challenge is determining how many ways we can construct such an array arr.</description></item><item><title>2251. Number of Flowers in Full Bloom</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/2251/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/algorithms-101/leetcode/hard/2251/</guid><description>LeetCode Problem 2251
Problem Statement In the given problem, we are presented with two arrays. The first, flowers, represents when each flower starts and stops being in full bloom. The second, people, indicates when each person arrives to see the flowers. Our task is to determine, for each person, how many flowers they will see in full bloom upon their arrival.
Naive Solution A straightforward approach might involve iterating over each person&amp;rsquo;s arrival time. For each time, we could iterate over the flowers list to count how many flowers are in full bloom.</description></item></channel></rss>