<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ec2 on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/ec2/</link><description>Recent content in Ec2 on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Personal page</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tags/ec2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>EC2</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/ec2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/aws-certified-developer-associate/ec2/</guid><description>About AWS EC2 AWS EC2 User Guide Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) - one of the most popular AWS services.
Allows:
to run different types of cloud instances and pay-per-use models. to control computing resources at the operating system level working in an Amazon computing environment. Digest EC2 &amp;amp; EBS EC2 (Elastic Compute Cloud) Instance EBS (Elastic Block Store) - Persistent storage volume AMI (Amazon Machine Image) - Packages OS and additional installations in a reusable template Instance and Instance Types: General Purpose (t-type and m-type), Compute Optimized(c-type), GPU Graphics, GPU Compute, Memory Optimized(r, × and z-type), and Storage Optimized(d, h and i-type) Purchasing Options: On Demand, Reserved, Scheduled, Spot, Dedicated Instance and Dedicated Host Spot: Partial hours are not billed if terminated by AWS EC2 Secure login information for your instances using key pairs Placement group: Cluster and Spread For root:</description></item><item><title>Setup OpenVPN Server on AWS EC2 Ubuntu</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/stories/002-openvpn-aws-ec2-setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/stories/002-openvpn-aws-ec2-setup/</guid><description>Today, I embarked on a journey to create an accessible, affordable, and easy-to-use VPN solution that anyone can set up on their devices using AWS.
Finding a reasonably priced solution was critical. I opted for Amazon&amp;rsquo;s t3a.nano ARM Ubuntu image, which costs ~$0.0047/hour ~ $3.8/month.
Various Amazon EC2 instances and their prices are listed on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s On-Demand Pricing page.
Here is the list of all Ubuntu AMI images to identify the appropriate image for the project. The selected image combined with the CloudFormation template, which was inspired by the AWS CloudFormation General Reference, provides a seamless and consistent user experience.</description></item></channel></rss>