<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Roadmaps on Roman Kurnovskii</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/</link><description>Recent content in Roadmaps on Roman Kurnovskii</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 &lt;a href="https://romankurnovskii.com">Roman Kurnovskii&lt;/a> personal page</copyright><atom:link href="https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Short description from article</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/disser/utils/text_2_short/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/disser/utils/text_2_short/</guid><description> Create</description></item><item><title/><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/apm-server/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/apm-server/readme/</guid><description>APM Server extension The APM Server receives data from APM agents and transforms them into Elasticsearch documents that can be visualised in Kibana.
Usage To include APM Server in the stack, run Docker Compose from the root of the repository with an additional command line argument referencing the apm-server-compose.yml file:
1$ docker-compose -f docker-compose.yml -f extensions/apm-server/apm-server-compose.yml up Meanwhile, you can navigate to the APM application in Kibana and follow the setup instructions to get started.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/curator/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/curator/readme/</guid><description>Curator Elasticsearch Curator helps you curate or manage your indices.
Usage If you want to include the Curator extension, run Docker Compose from the root of the repository with an additional command line argument referencing the curator-compose.yml file:
1$ docker-compose -f docker-compose.yml -f extensions/curator/curator-compose.yml up This sample setup demonstrates how to run curator every minute using cron.
All configuration files are available in the config/ directory.
Documentation Curator Reference</description></item><item><title/><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/enterprise-search/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/enterprise-search/readme/</guid><description>Enterprise Search extension Elastic Enterprise Search is a suite of products for search applications backed by the Elastic Stack.
Requirements 2 GB of free RAM, on top of the resources required by the other stack components and extensions. Enterprise Search exposes the TCP port 3002 for its Web UI and API.
Usage Generate an encryption key Enterprise Search requires one or more encryption keys to be configured before the initial startup. Failing to do so prevents the server from starting.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/filebeat/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/filebeat/readme/</guid><description>Filebeat Filebeat is a lightweight shipper for forwarding and centralizing log data. Installed as an agent on your servers, Filebeat monitors the log files or locations that you specify, collects log events, and forwards them either to Elasticsearch or Logstash for indexing.
Usage To include Filebeat in the stack, run Docker Compose from the root of the repository with an additional command line argument referencing the filebeat-compose.yml file:
1$ docker-compose -f docker-compose.yml -f extensions/filebeat/filebeat-compose.yml up Configuring Filebeat The Filebeat configuration is stored in config/filebeat.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/logspout/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/logspout/readme/</guid><description>Logspout extension Logspout collects all Docker logs using the Docker logs API, and forwards them to Logstash without any additional configuration.
Usage If you want to include the Logspout extension, run Docker Compose from the root of the repository with an additional command line argument referencing the logspout-compose.yml file:
1$ docker-compose -f docker-compose.yml -f extensions/logspout/logspout-compose.yml up In your Logstash pipeline configuration, enable the udp input and set the input codec to json:
1input { 2 udp { 3 port =&amp;gt; 5000 4 codec =&amp;gt; json 5 } 6} Documentation https://github.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/metricbeat/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/metricbeat/readme/</guid><description>Metricbeat Metricbeat is a lightweight shipper that you can install on your servers to periodically collect metrics from the operating system and from services running on the server. Metricbeat takes the metrics and statistics that it collects and ships them to the output that you specify, such as Elasticsearch or Logstash.
Usage To include Metricbeat in the stack, run Docker Compose from the root of the repository with an additional command line argument referencing the metricbeat-compose.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/90daysofdevops/monitoring/elastic-stack/extensions/readme/</guid><description>Extensions Third-party extensions that enable extra integrations with the Elastic stack.</description></item><item><title>Docs</title><link>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/archive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://romankurnovskii.com/en/tracks/archive/</guid><description>This page contains an archive of all posts.</description></item></channel></rss>